Welcome Living Mana Church family. Thank
you to the faithful that stuck with us.
We apologize for our technical delay,
but Nicole, you took the words right out
of my mouth. We got to experience all
the fruits of the spirit this morning.
patience, love, longsuffering,
joy even while we're waiting
and God blessed. He blessed because we
are here now. Uh so please I we sorry
don't have time to shout everybody out
which we'd love to do where you're
viewing from. There was one the very
first one when we were uh we could see
some of the chat what you guys were
saying and uh I saw Portugal
>> I was like that's cool all the way from
Europe so I'm sorry we don't have time
to do any others though but welcome
happy Sabbath again and you guys were
fun to watch in the chat because we
could still see you guys playing the
game of all the fruits of the spirit. We
just love love you guys were acting like
it was a hangout day like y'all were
just hanging out in the chat so that was
cool. Um, but we're happy to be here.
Happy Sabbath. We have some second
readings. We want to have officially
um have two people join Living Man
Church and then we're going to jump
right into our Sabbath school because
our technical difficulty time took away
from any other greetings. But we
definitely want to
get to our um second readings. Okay.
>> Amen.
>> We have Thomas Harris from Oakwood
University Church and Thomas is already
very active here at Living Matter
Church. He was my Hangouts leader this
last Sunday. So Hangouts was great and
Thomas you did a great job. you had our
minds thinking and so [laughter]
uh it was great and so you did a great
job. Um and last week was his birthday
so happy belated birthday. He was
excited that the first reading was read
on his birthday. So that's that's pretty
cool.
>> Um and then for the second reading
we have Elina Rodriguez Ruez from the uh
Morirana Spanish 7day Adventist Church.
That's the second reading of
>> that's the second. So we have Thomas and
Elana
>> uh from the Morirana Spanish 7th Avenue
Church and Thomas is from Oakwood
University Church.
>> Okay.
>> So we have those two.
>> All right. So we are going to entertain
a motion uh to accept Thomas and Elena
um both into the fellowship of the uh
Living Mana online church
>> officially.
>> Officially. So, um, we'll entertain a
motion first,
then we'll do a second, uh, and then
we'll vote. Asked to put the ones in the
chat. So, we are waiting. Y'all are
already welcoming them and we haven't
even, uh, but that's fine. Go ahead.
Jump ahead. That is all.
>> You have a motion, right? Do you have a
motion?
>> I don't think we I don't think I saw a
motion yet. So, okay, we got a motion.
>> I was going to I'll second it.
>> Okay, so we got a motion. and a second.
>> Um, and so we'll go ahead and let's
start putting that one in the chat
>> to welcome both Thomas and
>> Elena.
And uh, here come the ones.
>> Yes. And we are so happy to have you
guys officially joining us.
>> Amen.
>> It was so cool. That was my second time
having Thomas. He was my um, Hangouts
leader.
>> My second time I went. This was my third
time last week. So that was cool. So
Thomas, I know you're very active and
>> Yes. already. And
>> yeah,
>> so we praise God uh for both of you,
Thomas. Um
>> Elena
>> and Elena. Um please, the Living Matter
of Church family. Uh give them a very
warm and special welcome,
>> welcome in the chat. and we are looking
forward to having you guys continue to
serve and to help us here at Living Mana
Church to help this ministry and this
church continue to go into all of the
world. So, welcome. Welcome officially
to Living Mana Church. You are official
members now.
>> Praise God.
>> Amen.
>> You know, because of time I was like,
"Oh, we could I was like actually I
didn't I'm dishonest. I didn't think of
considering skipping it because I think
Satan
>> doesn't want me to say what I have to
say today.
>> So,
>> the shirt says if it's not the will of
God, it is it's not the will of God if
it goes against the word of God.
>> Amen. So, all right guys, the first time
I'm wearing this and I had something
happen this week that um I felt like it
was kind of perfect. Uh the shirt was
perfect. Um, so I was sharing with
someone um, you know, about Matthew 18.
They needed to speak to someone and I
was like, you know, you need to Matthew
18. Um, and I just followed up with, you
know, you can't Matthew 18 with an
attitude. I'll just keep it I'll just
say it like that. Like you can't Matthew
you you can't use Matthew 18
>> if your heart isn't right towards that
person even though they hurt you. You
have to spend time in prayer in God's
face saying, "Lord, help me to have the
right spirit to do Matthew 18." Because
you you have to go, let's put this way.
This is what I told the person. You have
to go to the person with the spirit of
Jesus.
>> You're not going with an attitude
rolling your neck. I'm acting like it's
females or having like a a macho mean
attitude if it's a guy. You you that's
not you have to go in the spirit of
Jesus for it to work. That's why God
gave us this. Um, and so many times in a
church setting, they we don't use
Matthew 18 the way that we should. And
even outside of a church setting, just
with our family, friends, whoever. And
it's because we don't have the spirit of
Jesus in us.
>> And if we don't have the spirit of the
spirit of Jesus in us, it will not work.
>> And I tell my, this is something I use
with my couples, like you have to have
your conversations with empathy or
understanding. you start soft startups
instead of hard startups. But if you if
you come like we always say at your
spouse or at your church member or at
your friend or co-orker whoever sideways
what you're wanting you're not going to
get out of it. Like you just when it
comes to Matthew 18, you just want them
to see or let them know that you know
that that one thing or happened that
that really bothered me. Um but you're
coming in a spirit of love
>> so their guards are down. They can
really hear your heart and your pain and
the spirit of Christ that you have and
you're using, you want that to bounce
off of you and transcend to them. I
mean, they have to have their own,
>> you know, thing with God. But that
example or that you starting that like
love awakens love
>> um will
>> should melt their hearts.
>> But that but you have to go there's no
chance if you don't go in that spirit.
Yeah.
>> So many ways.
>> That's what I wanted to share today. So
my point is that your the spirit of
Jesus has to be in your heart
>> for it to work. It's not
>> um the word of God
>> without the spirit of Jesus. Yeah.
>> So if you try to be like, "Oh, I'm
Matthew 18, but you Matthew 18 with an
attitude." Yeah. You didn't Matthew 18.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Amen.
>> All right.
>> All right. All right. We do have guests,
guys. And we are talking about peace.
And we had to practice peace
>> for a whole hour.
>> Patience, but you had to have peace to
have patience.
>> All right. You had to have patience, but
we had to have peace, too. All right.
There they go. Our lovely. Amen. You
guys,
>> you guys practice long suffering.
>> I hope you were taking your notes like
this today. [laughter] There should be
no dead air. We're going to let you guys
>> All right. So, let's pray. Heavenly
Father, thank you, Lord Father.
>> Thank you, Lord, for
>> uh giving us opportunity, Lord, to come
and worship before you today. Lord, we
thank you for um helping us deal with
the technical difficulties. And Lord, in
the short time that we have Sabbath
school this morning, I pray that it will
be a blessing to those who are watching,
Lord, and that uh you will just speak
through um all the participants today,
Lord. Um and we pray this in Jesus name.
Amen.
>> Amen. And I would not tech team who
worked tirelessly for an hour to get us
on. So thank you tech team, broadcast
team, whatever name you want to go by.
>> So do you want to do the introduction?
>> Well God um
>> we are still on the fruit of joy.
>> Oh I know we finished joy.
We didn't finish Joy, did we?
>> I thought we would. We did finish Joy
last week.
>> We only read one sentence.
>> You're right. We didn't finish Joy.
>> I did not rush it. Let's go back to joy.
Let's have joy. We need joy this
morning. Anyway, let's go back to And no
wonder you guys were caught. The the
viewing audience knew what was up
because I kept seeing joy, joy, joy. I
was like, "Oh, they don't realize we're
on pizza."
>> Yeah.
>> In my mind, we talked so much about joy,
but we didn't we didn't discuss it quite
a bit. We just we didn't touch all of
it.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So, let's pick up.
>> Okay.
>> So,
um we are
>> pull this up. Yeah. Where's Brother
Kashif? Is he on or
>> All right. So he actually, this is a
sentence I read last week and then we
just stopped right there and it was this
um we struggle to do what is a burden.
We love to do what is a joy.
The spirit of joy is another is another
fruit warriors against self must not
only possess but master. And we kind of
spent the whole Sabbath school if I
remember correctly. Um
>> that first sentence and I remember
Melinda being like, "Yeah, we only got
to two words the night before." Okay,
got it. I do remember.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, um we are going to
uh continue on. I'm going to read the
this first paragraph,
>> okay?
>> And then we'll let the uh let our guests
jump in and share. And we're going to
see if we can work on our volume because
we see everybody in the chat saying your
volume. Your volume. So,
>> it's mine, not yours.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, it is
>> both of ours.
>> Okay.
>> All right. But let me read this super
loud.
Um, [laughter] not only must we fight
against self, we must enjoy it. That's
That's another stop right there
sentence.
enjoying fighting.
[clears throat]
That's a hard thing to do.
>> And it's a decision because just this
last hour,
I had to and I wasn't going to be
frustrated with one person. It was no
one person's fault or anything, but we
weren't live. So, it was like I was
tempted
to be very frustrated
>> just because of
technical issues.
>> Anybody ever
>> choose to be like, "Okay, joy." And and
they helped me because I kept in the
chat, too. Let's get a reminder.
>> Anybody ever feel like throwing a
computer?
>> Oh, yeah. [laughter]
Sometimes computers will just test. Do
you really have the fruit of the spirit?
You can actually see if you have the
fruit of the spirit just by you interact
how you interact with your computer when
it's not working.
I'm sure we all have
>> absolutely
>> moments of repentance when it comes to
dealing with our computers. But you must
love
this fight. In other words, it cannot be
a fight that you enter in. Remember how
David
when Goliath took that first step
towards David that in David's mind he
was like yes it's on.
>> Yeah.
>> And he runs
>> towards
>> Goliath.
>> Yes.
>> Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Yeah.
>> You know we can't hear Melinda.
>> Melinda you're muted.
Melinda, you're you're muted. I don't
know if you can hear us, but you're
muted. We can't hear you.
>> We know we can hear Terry, but Michaela,
I want to make sure we can hear you. Can
you just say happy Sabbath or
>> No, we can't hear either one of the of
the young ladies. So,
>> Oh, wow.
>> That's important.
>> But you can't hear me.
>> We can't hear.
>> We can hear you, Terry.
>> Audience, can you hear uh Brother Terry?
Happy Sabbath audience.
>> I think they can because they saying
they can hear you loud. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So, broadcast team, if you could
please work on Melinda and Michaela's
sound.
>> Okay. Um
I know Melinda was about to say
something, but Terry, may you could pick
up.
>> Yes. all the time. I feel like throwing
my computers, but [laughter]
I know I've learned that it's a lot of
times for me anyway, it's not the
computer, it's me. And so, uh, I've
gotten better. So, no, I don't throw it
because I don't want to have to buy
another one. [laughter]
But uh joy, you know, this week I was uh
at work and I was thinking about the joy
and I was thinking, "Oh man, we're going
to go on to something else." I told
everybody we're going to be talking
about patience today, but I was wrong.
Sorry, saints. It's joy. And so, but uh
Psalm 51 came across my mind when King
David said, "Restore unto me the joy of
thy salvation, and uphold me with thy
free spirit." And you know, uh, I
remembered thinking about that this
week. What keeps me joyful is a
perpetual
attitude of repentance, right? And I I
got a good revelation on repentance
that, you know, usually when we hear
repentance, we're like, uh, oh, got to
get right. Right. But repentance is
really good news. It's God saying, "Hey,
I want you and I want you to come to me
and I'm going to draw you to me and I'm
going to give you this gift to bring you
to me." And that's for somebody like me.
And you know, I've I've been the chief
of sinners, you know, and so salvation
is still the joy of my heart. It's the
it's the joy of my life. I wanted to
stay that way. And so when I maintain an
attitude of repentance and think about,
man, how good God has been to me. I
didn't get what I deserved. I got mercy,
you know, and then I got what I don't
deserve. I got grace. And so, man, I am
I'm just I want to stay fueled by that
joy that that'll be the foundation of
everything I do. That God has brought
salvation to my life and he wants to use
me to reflect that to other people. So,
I want to try to be joyous. I'm not
always joyous. Y'all don't always see
it, but I can be quite a communion
sometimes. [laughter]
But,
you have to ask Sister Amber about that
more than anybody else. But uh
>> of course
>> I do know that uh I have joy because you
know God is God is real in our lives and
uh I'm I'm so thankful for it and being
a part of living mana being a part of
having you guys a part of my life I mean
it's absolutely incredible uh when I get
outside of self and actually sit back
and look at pastor meer and look at
sister and living mana and this
beautiful uh family of God and the work
that he's given us to do. You you got to
rejoice, you know. So,
>> Amen.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> I'm going to I'm going to add something
here. I'm just going to continue reading
and I don't know if um if the other
guests are able to unmute themselves
yet, but
>> um
>> not them unmute themselves, but
whatever's going on with the issues.
>> So, it says here, righteousness must not
only be our duty, it must be our
pastime. It must become our hobby as
well as our mission. The fight against
self is not a 9-to-f5 job.
>> There is no clock to punch out
>> except the clock of death.
>> Whatever we are called to do
all day will certainly become a burden
unless we actually enjoy doing it. Mhm.
>> And I think for a lot of Christians, um,
[clears throat] righteousness
is sometimes worse than a 9-to-five job.
>> It's a Sabbath job
>> and only for a couple hours.
>> So, we punch the clock when we when we
get into church.
>> Hi.
>> Happy.
>> Oh, I'm blessed.
>> Yeah. and and you keep that up for as
long as a church service lasts
>> two and a half, three hours.
>> And sometimes we're not even good at
doing that.
>> Yeah.
>> And so
you go out, you know, you're living
so much of the week not
exhibiting the fruit of the spirit,
not fighting against self. But when it
comes to church, all right, time to
punch in.
>> People said they loved um Brother
Terry's uh transparency. And I'm just
thinking I'm be a little transparent
here. [laughter] Just a dink. Well, you
know, you guys, we have four kids,
right? And so, well, they're adults now,
but when they were kids and we're a
pastor's family and trying to get on
church on time
>> was a little challenging sometimes,
making sure hair is done,
>> dress, you know, getting them all
dressed and fed and all the things you
have to do. And so I just remember
getting frustrated on Sabbath mornings,
not really having a joyful spirit all
the time and driving to church.
The kids didn't experience a joyful
spirit. You're silent just probably
thinking about your sermon or whatever.
And then we get there and then you're
you have to you you turn on the really
fake joy spirit.
>> Yeah.
So, I know other people can relate, but
>> yeah,
>> I that's not what we should do. I'm
saying that to say don't do that. And if
you're doing that, pray to God
>> and ask him to help you.
>> And I think that's it. Yeah. I mean,
it's easy to get
>> cuz the example to the kids wasn't
great.
>> Yeah. It's it's easy especially when you
have
>> now
>> especially when you have little
children.
>> That's what I'm saying.
>> And
>> it's hard.
>> Yeah.
>> But it doesn't have it's not impossible.
>> It's not. It's not. And God doesn't want
us to behave how I would behave when I'd
get frustrated.
>> Doesn't want that.
>> How we behave when we get frustrated
because we all get frustrated.
>> We all get frustrated. But I mean, here
it is. I'm going to church Sabbath
morning.
>> But again,
>> it's the Sabbath, but my attitude isn't
right. I'm not I'm not having joy. So,
it doesn't have to be our exact
situation with little kids, but just
Yeah.
>> I'm going off of what you were saying.
You get to church and you turn it on and
that's a decision. So, you make a
decision, right? When you get to church,
you can make a decision every day when
you get up and surrender that thing
because you decide to
>> to do it at that time.
>> Yep. Yep.
>> So, it's always a choice before you.
>> All right. Our guests
>> I like that. Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Yeah. I I I really like that that um
that what you guys just brought out. If
I'm able to turn it on at church, then
I'm able to turn it on all the time.
Yeah.
>> Right.
>> It's a choice.
>> It's a choice. If that joy is coming out
then then I can tap into that joy all
the time because it's there.
>> Thank you. Thank you for sharing that
first lady. That that that is powerful
you know um because there there are
those times when we are relaxed and you
know we're not in the formal setting.
We're not in the church setting. We're
not thinking about the fact that all of
heaven's watching. The entire universe
is watching. We're think about people
are watching. But reality, God's always
watching, you know, and I want to
perform for the audience of one.
>> Yeah. We need to care about God is
always there. We don't want to Yeah.
He's always watching.
>> Powerful point. Praise God for y'all
bringing that out this morning.
Beautiful. Yes. So, um, and I don't
remember if we talked about this last
week, but we to we, you know, addressed
the idea, I believe, that the Bible says
for the joy that was set before him. We
did talk about that. how Jesus
>> looked forward. His joy was not based on
the things of this world.
>> It was based on what he saw coming.
>> And so we did talk about how so for so
many of us, our joy is based on if
things are good, then I'll have joy. If
things are bad, Amen.
>> then I'm not going to have joy.
>> And that goes along with because our
viewing audience is part of this. It
goes along I think Zadina, happy
Sabbath. Good to see you here. She said,
"It's hard for me to show joy when
frustrated." And I wanted to say to her
what I should have done, what you can do
when you're feeling frustrated is take
just
put myself on a mental timeout. Take a
deep breath and
you're feeling frustrated, but you can
take that again. Take that deep breath,
do a mental reset, and then choose joy.
>> Amen. We're just being as practical as
possible here.
>> Yep.
>> All right, let's see.
>> Don't feel frustrated. Yay. Let's see.
Okay, we got Kashif, too.
>> Eminem, can we hear you? Kashiv, can we
hear you?
>> Can you guys hear me?
>> Yay.
>> All right, Michaela.
>> Michaela.
>> Hi.
>> We hear Michaela. I don't hear Melinda.
You hear us, but we don't hear you.
>> No, we still don't hear you.
>> We still don't hear you, Melinda.
>> They're going to continue to work on
you, Melinda. I know. Don't get Don't
get frustrated. [laughter]
>> We're I know it's I know it's
temptation. Take the deep breath. It's
is We're all still a little frustrated
because I know you guys
>> have something to Well, you were already
starting to share and we weren't able to
hear you. Yeah.
>> Did you have something you want to
share?
>> No, no, no. Go ahead, guys. I know.
Okay. Michaela or Kashif, either one of
you, please, if you have something to
share, please, please do.
>> Oh, yeah. This is um something that I
always speak on. Oh, Melinda, go ahead.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Okay, Michaela, he's gonna let ladies go
first and she's gonna go.
>> Okay. Um, yeah, I think joy it's kind of
like
an energy source for the fight. Maybe
kind of like it gives momentum.
Um,
>> it's hard to fight without that constant
energy source. I think that motivation
>> of joy.
>> Yeah,
>> that's just what I was thinking.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I'm going to take it back to David
again
>> with him running towards Goliath. Like
this was a passion of his,
>> you know, this wasn't, oh man, I have to
fight. It was like
the desire
was
was overwhelming.
>> And I think that's the kind of spirit
that we need to have.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, we are all of us have a
Goliath.
>> Yes.
>> And our Goliath is older than us.
>> The old you is o is bigger and older
than the new you.
>> Yes. The new you was just born when you
were born again, right? So the old you
is always older
>> and he's your giant.
>> She's your giant.
>> But we have to have that spirit of David
>> going up against going up against
Goliath.
>> Um
that gives us that momentum.
>> Right.
>> Right. To keep that fight up.
>> Yes. Okay. Kashie, I know you had
something to share.
Yeah. You guys hear me?
>> Yeah.
>> Yes, we can hear you.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You know, this is um I
always I always speak of how Jesus wants
us to have joy. You know, he said,
"These things have I spoken unto you
that my joy might remain in you and that
your joy might be full." So, it's not
just to be just not just to have joy,
but we'll be full of joy all the time.
And even the verse before that, he said,
"Just as he kept his father's
commandments, you know, so we are to do
as well." So it links directly to
obedience and um that delight that we
have in following God's law. It goes
hand in hand. It's the same way that I
like to link the fruits of the spirit as
well. You know, if if if you don't have
one, if you're having trouble with one,
then you know, you you you kind of like
you break all
>> the same way as ten commandments, you
know.
>> Yep. So that joy is, you know, it just
feels well for me anyway, I always laugh
at myself when I get upset or I feel
frustration coming out like don't you
don't you find yourself feeling stupid
right now? Why you behaving? [laughter]
>> Yeah. So
>> it just doesn't make any sense to stay
in that space of frustration or anything
negative like that. So I just um I cut
it short as soon as possible and just
remember what Christ said. You know,
we're Christians. We're supposed to be
joyful.
>> People supposed to be looking at us and
see, well, wow, something is really
different about these people. Why are
they always so happy?
>> We do look foolish, Kashie. We have
adult temper tantrums
>> and it looks very childlike. Yes. Yes.
Melinda,
>> there she goes.
>> Hallelujah. Praise God.
>> Awesome. Please share.
>> Awesome. Praise God.
>> Amen.
>> Okay, so I'm sorry. I wanted to say
something about the sentence that pastor
Iva read. Not only must we fight self,
we must enjoy it. I think something
that's important is that
when we fight self or just generally any
battle that we fight, we have to have
victory in that battle to
have enjoyed fighting or even to enjoy
the next battle because if you're in a
constant line of defeat, you're just
going to get frustrated with battling.
So, I think it's important to trust God
and his um um his delivering power to
give you victory after victory so that
you can keep um having joy because I
think joy is something that I think we
talked last time about uh situational or
conditional joy. Yeah,
>> something like that. And I think that
even spiritually
there is there is a type of like there's
I feel I feel like in spiritual sense
there's like two joys. Okay. There's a
joy like when I've won a battle and then
there's a joy when just for being saved
like you know experiencing salvation.
And I think the joy of winning the
battle is one that God gives us to
encourage us to keep going you know.
>> Yeah. that I think that's powerful
because you know
how often do we actually celebrate when
we get a victory over something. M
>> I mean when you look at you know
look at the sports world somebody scores
a basket somebody scores a you know a
goal somebody makes a touchdown
>> somebody gets the point
>> like the celebration is like you know
you can see it you can
>> hear it
>> you can hear it
>> and everybody's cheering it. Mhm.
>> How do we respond
when we
get even a small victory,
>> right? Even what we could what we might
consider a small victory,
>> if we if we celebrate the small victory
with joy,
>> I think it's almost like a
self-propelling
every time I It's like an addiction. So,
you know when uh uh they call it um an
adrenal like a like an adrenaline hit,
right?
>> Your dopamine, that's what I meant.
Dopamine hit.
>> You know, you do something, you really
enjoy that,
>> you're looking for the next dopamine
hit, right? You're looking for the next
>> time you can experience that thing
again. But if we're not training our
minds to see victory
>> as a dopamine hit, as a, oh man, that
felt good.
>> So good.
>> That felt good.
>> Um, then
we take for granted victories.
>> And when you take for granted victories,
>> you're not valuing them
>> to the point that can actually help
change your character,
>> right? change your spirit, change your
disposition.
>> And I think that that rejoicing or that
joy, that cheering, it happens before
the thing even happens. I talked about
it last week about meaning like you're
starting like, "All right." And I I'm
thinking about my mind when you just
were sharing that automatically went to
to Sean because he was like that. Like
he has videos of like when he's in a
situation, he's like, "Okay, God. All
right. Mhm.
>> I'm excited to see what you're about to
do now. Like, let's just wait. So, I
mean, that type of
>> of spirit. Um, even when you're in the
situation, like you you start pre-
praising and then when it happens,
you're like, "God, I knew you were going
to do it and here we are."
>> Pre- praise.
>> I like that term. That was like the the
best lesson that
um my prayer spiritual mentor um Janet
Page taught me.
>> Yeah. Praise the of the storm.
>> I like that.
>> Um all right. Did anyone want to jump
in?
>> Yeah.
>> Pre praise.
>> That's powerful.
>> Amen.
>> Pre praise.
>> That's what keeps us sane in this sinful
world. Like, and it's it's I'm sorry,
guys. I know you're about to go. It's
exercising our faith
>> right away. You have to have faith to
pre- praise. Okay, guys.
>> Amen.
>> Um, for me, that's really relatable.
Like, I do something, I accomplish
something, and I'm like, okay, that's
what I was supposed to do anyway. You
know what I mean? It's what I'm supposed
to do. So it's not there's not that joy
necessarily. Um
but it's the whole mentality of it like
if you're doing it
with the rest of the fruits of the
spirit. So you're doing it because you
love it
>> because you love why you're doing it.
Then you have joy in it and you want
like you just said you want to do it
again and again because you love doing
it and there's joy in.
>> Amen. It's not It's not a burden.
>> It's not a burden.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> Uh could I go back to pre- praise for a
minute?
>> Yeah.
>> Uh because you know I I am convinced
that starting with me, we don't praise
enough.
>> We don't.
>> And we don't get in the habit of
praising. You know, we live in a world
where the love of many is growing cold
and people are just meaner today. and
and uh there's more of an aggressive
spirit in everything and every in this
world that we live in, you know, and
these fruit of the spirit are really
needed now more than ever. And so when I
when I think about pre- praise, I'm
thinking about Philippians where it
says, "Be anxious for nothing, but in
everything prayer, supplication, and
giving of thanks, let your requests be
made known." So God's setting us up
right there, telling us, "Hey, start
giving thanks and praising even before
you come to me with whatever it is you
need to ask or whatever it is you're
about to go through. Make that a way of
life." And so what that does is that
takes me back to what Pastor said
earlier in the book about practice.
It's practicing and training for the
battle that's coming. So, if I'm not
training, if if I'm not learning how to
use the spear and I'm not learning how
to use the shield and I'm not learning
how to throw sling that rock, you know,
I've got to do that stuff in advance.
And and it's today I'm thankful that
we're talking about it because it's
reminding me uh when pastor said that uh
the fight against self is not a
nineto-five. There is no clock to punch
out, right?
>> We have to understand that that fight is
going on until the day that Jesus
appears in those clouds, right? And so
it reminds me of uh 1 Timothy 6:12. We
all know it. It says, "Fight the good
fight of faith, lay hold on eternal
life, where to thou are also called and
has professed a good profession before
many witnesses." And I love this verse
right here, what Paul said. He said,"I
give thee charge in the sight of God who
quickenth all things and before Christ
Jesus who before Pontis Pilate's witness
a good con confession that thou keep
this commandment without spot
unrebukeable until the appearing of the
Lord Jesus Christ." What commandment?
Fight. The commandment only imperative
he gave in that passage was fight. And
so he said fight till I come.
>> Fight till I come. And so when I look at
a boxer's I was looking at something the
other day where the boxer was deciding
whether or not he could beat the champ.
He had to watch a lot of film on this
guy and study this guy and prepare ahead
of time and get ready for the fight even
before it happened.
>> So pre- praise.
>> Yeah.
>> And you know watching the film. Wow.
>> Um we we ought to be watching our own
film, right? to see, hey, how does the
enemy move? Where does he where does he
get the upper hand on me?
>> It's it's amazing what happens when you
watch film. And you can see, okay, this
is this is where I need to get better.
This is where I fell. This is where, you
know, my my weak spot was. And as you
watch film
and as you begin to gain those
victories, like teams that win a lot are
going to love playing. Teams that lose a
lot,
>> here goes another game.
>> And if they win, they watched a lot of
film. Mhm.
>> But I think there's two films to watch
to
to contemplate like what you're saying
where where's my triggers or where does
Satan get in to get me to um to fall,
you know, and where is he successful
there?
>> And then there's the film um of faith
like Ellen White says like our Israel's
biggest uh sin is that they forgot Mhm.
>> what God had done for them. So when when
you're in the trial, remember what God
has done in the past.
>> That's going to help you with your joy
because you're going to be like, "All
right, God. I know you have me. You're
going to remember." And then you're
going to have faith.
>> But then it's also to watch the film, if
you will, and just with, you know, just
thinking and praying and meditating with
God. Okay, this is how the enemy gets
me.
>> So that you know what to pray and say,
"Okay, God, help me correct that here.
help me to in that area. So those two
films
>> can I interrupt here?
>> Y
>> I think that what uh sister Tante said
is is powerful in the sense that um we
have to forget that there are we cannot
forget that there are two films to
watch. Number one, our own film where is
the devil getting me? Where are my
weaknesses? Where am I losing? And then
number two, and I feel like this is
probably
>> shall I say it's the more important one
because we're in danger if we constantly
watch our own film over and over and
over and over again. We're in danger of
getting discouraged and be like I can
never beat this like I always fail in
this joy.
>> And the second film is the second film
is
>> Jesus and how he overcame temptation and
that he is able to overcome temptation.
And I feel like that one's almost films
>> on the on the screen. [laughter] I don't
know. Yeah,
>> maybe is multiple levels, you know.
>> Amen.
>> But I think it's important to watch the
Jesus film and to see him overcome these
temptations and be like, "Yeah, he can
do that for me, too."
>> Yeah.
>> Amen.
>> Sister W has a statement where she says
that we should spend a thoughtful hour
every day watching the film.
>> That's right. She should
>> a thoughtful hour. I mean, she doesn't
say watching the film, but you get the
point.
>> Meditating on the life of Christ from
the manger
>> to the cross,
>> especially the final scene,
>> especially the closing scenes.
>> And she says, "As we watch, we will come
imbued with his spirit."
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Yeah.
>> This is fun. We're tracking off each
other. We're bouncing off each other. So
>> anybody jump in here? Whoever whoever
wants to share.
>> Yeah,
>> no pressure.
>> Remembering that sermon she said,
"Pastor M preached this message in the
faith sermon earlier this year."
Actually, I actually preached that
sermon for the first time.
>> Probably it was in England.
>> Um
>> I really don't remember.
>> The very first time we went to England
and I did the whole faith world series
>> and that's 20 years ago.
>> 20 years ago. Yeah. [laughter]
>> Wow. Yep.
>> And he's remembering. I'm not
remembering. I remember going I do
remember that.
>> I do.
>> I remember you doing that series. I just
Yeah.
>> So
I think that I mean we cannot exhaust
joy but
>> No. And we have we've made provisions.
We have about 10 more minutes even
though we were late. We have 10 minutes.
>> Okay. So actually you know what? I don't
think we should start. No, no, no. We
can start peace.
>> Oh, we that's we're Okay. Well, let me
see if Well, let's see if there's
anything else on Joy.
>> All right.
>> I'm going to jump down the piece.
>> The first. Okay.
>> Okay.
>> So, uh let me read the first paragraph.
And it seems like I just read the first
paragraph and then we just like But
let's
>> the first line. Why don't you just try
the first line? Let's see if we
>> Yeah. The first two words. Yeah.
>> All right. The first two words, the
spirit. Here's the here's the actual
title of this section. No war.
>> Yes.
>> No peace.
No war. No peace.
>> I think we should just don't go no
further.
>> We could probably go on that.
>> Just go. [laughter]
>> Yeah.
>> When you guys hear that, what speaks to
you?
>> All of it. But how does it I should say
how does it speak to you?
>> One thing that I learned
specifically from pastor and sister is
um when they did
was it anger or marriage? I believe it
was marriage through the sanctuary
>> and the labor especially with regards to
washing things away before they happen.
Mhm.
>> I think that works with any fruit of the
spirit.
>> You know, if you you picture up a
particular situation that you know
you're going to get involved with during
the day or whatnot, you think about all
the negative ways it could go
>> and you you find love in the way that
you know you're able to wash a possible
negative way out out of it. You find
that joy. You find that peace the same
way. And therefore your mind is in that
state where you can just walk into it
and you allow the Holy Spirit to work
for you. That has worked tremendously
for me.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> So something that stands out to me about
this is how um the book mentions in the
first couple paragraphs where Jesus was
in the boat and he rested in the storm.
And the next verse that it um gives you
shows is um come unto me all you who are
heavy laden and I will give you rest.
And I think that is my absolute favorite
part about the spirit of peace is that
this isn't something that like I need to
fight for. I I don't know maybe that's
the wrong expression. I'm not sure if
you guys know what I mean because peace
is obtained by war against self,
>> but it's also not war.
>> And does that make Do you know what I
mean? Cuz like peace and war, those are
like
>> not together, you know?
>> Yeah. Exactly. So, it's like, wait, I
have to go to war to get peace, but then
I have peace and I'm not
>> at war. Like, I don't know. Does someone
want to like elaborate on that?
>> I guess when you're tempted,
>> you automatically
don't have peace. You have a little
battle. So, you're basically, that's how
I saw it. Like, you're at war at that
moment. But to get peace, you got to go
through a little war.
>> Yeah. Uh, not a little.
>> I mean, when I say little, I mean, well,
God is bigger than
>> than than than Satan. So,
>> yeah.
>> Compared to God, it's little. that
it's it's a battle to choose because you
don't all I put it this way, it's only a
war if it's a battle to choose the peace
right away when you're tempted. I mean,
eventually you get you get to that with
certain temptations.
>> And then there's others that, you know,
you we're always going higher. We're
always getting better. So, I don't want
to say a new temptation, but a current
one that you're working on could be more
of a battle than an old one. Does that
make sense? I'm [laughter] saying
>> I'll say this
>> in my head, but I hope I don't know if
it came out.
>> The war
is a battle of peace.
>> So, so in other words,
>> you start with peace.
>> Wants to knock you off your
>> Do you know what I'm saying?
>> Yeah.
>> Like Zad, I'm sorry. Zadena had put in
the chat she wakes up with peace or
joyful or joy joy
>> with which is peace and then
within a couple hours something happens
and she can't get back to that space. So
that's what I'm saying talking about
>> what you're waring you're waring to
maintain peace.
>> Your war is to rest.
>> Your fight your work is to rest. Your
war is to rest.
>> So
>> you better than me. Thank you. would
play a a game with the kids sometime and
it was a game I just totally made up.
It's probably a stupid game,
>> but it worked.
>> And the game was this.
>> You can't itch for the next two minutes.
And then I just touch them.
>> With the big kids or little kids?
>> With when they were little?
>> No. And the big kids. Both. All four
kids. Okay. Okay.
>> And you know, I mean, they're like, I'm
not going to itch. And then like
>> in 15 seconds they're like all of a
sudden wait a minute where did that itch
feeling come from?
>> Why do I feel [laughter] like itch in my
back right now? I'm not going to itch my
back. And and it would just be war and
then it would be and then finally
and sometimes it's like the the battle
>> been thinking about an itch. The battle
right the battle was I can't itch that
itch. [laughter] I cannot itch that.
Some of y'all probably want to itch
right now. So it be all of a sudden
[laughter]
my neck feels like it's got to itch.
>> And a lot of times that's how temptation
works, right?
>> Like Satan will put the idea in your
mind. You weren't even thinking about
you were just minding your own business
and then boom.
>> And now you feel like you have to itch.
And the fight, the warfare is don't
itch.
>> Don't itch those ears.
>> Don't itch that thing. Don't itch. It it
will feel good in the itch,
>> but afterward it's only gonna get worse.
>> The war of peace
is the war to fight.
>> Somebody said they're itching right now.
[laughter]
>> Everybody put a one in the chat
>> if you're itching.
>> If you're itching right now,
>> you see how powerful the mind is. You're
like my
>> Somebody said my back is itching.
[laughter]
>> Just put a one in the chat. You're just
like, I am itching. Why am I itching
right now? All of a sudden,
>> pastor wouldn't have said it. I wouldn't
have shared the story. I wouldn't be
ashamed.
>> But that's that's how like that's our
battle, right? How do I maintain
rest?
>> Um I have a sermon where
where I talk about how the ten
commandments is all about resting.
>> God's like, "Don't do anything. Just
rest."
>> Yeah. Sabatismos. Yeah. Just chill. Just
stop.
>> The ten commandments is about giving us
rest from lying, rest from stealing,
rest from killing. Right? We are resting
from the works of the flesh.
>> Our battle is to rest.
>> Amen.
>> That's the war. That's the act of
warfare. The act of warfare is just stay
still. Don't move. Just stay still.
>> Don't itch. Don't move. My battle is
really pretty simple.
>> It's to rest.
>> It's to just rest
>> and let God fight the battle.
>> It's that peace. That peace is,
>> you know, on the tombstone. Rest in
peace.
>> Our goodness
>> is to stay dead.
>> Because the flesh [snorts] is trying to
resurrect.
>> Flesh is like, "Come on, come to life."
>> Satan
>> Satan has resurrection power. But it's
bad resurrection power.
>> Amen.
>> You know, he he's not in the he's not in
the chat saying it right now, but I can
hear brother Kirk. You know, Brother
Kirk is always saying it. We are
fighting from a position of victory.
>> We already have that victory.
>> Amen.
>> Brother Kirk says it all the time.
>> Yeah. Amen. Amen.
We're gonna You know what? That's going
to be your closing remark if that's
okay. I want to let everybody else have
a closing remark just for time. Just to
keep our time our time right.
>> Um Melinda Michaela Kashif if you have
any closing uh remarks
>> and we'll pick up
>> about on peace. Yeah. Next week
>> because we just read the title.
>> We just read the title
>> and I guess we could just [laughter]
summarize this whole thing just by the
title. But
>> yes,
>> we'll get into
>> that was an introduction guys,
>> right?
>> Yeah. I'll just say the last thing I
want to say that um when pastor
mentioned on the gravestones rest in
peace that that should apply to us and
our death to self every morning it
should be like okay rest in peace and
then Jesus just takes over with his
spirit and breathes into us the breath
of new life
>> and then we go on living with that new
life.
>> Amen.
>> Well said.
>> Yes. Okay,
Michaela Kashif, if you want to jump in
there. Okay, go ahead.
>> Uh, so I'm really looking forward to
piece. This is probably my favorite one
we've looked at so far.
>> Um,
and I'll probably say my main thought
for next week, but yeah.
>> Okay. All right.
>> Yeah, looking at Psalms 23
blew me away through this topic of
peace.
>> Amen.
Amen.
>> We're looking forward to what you have
to share for next week. And Kashie, do
you have any closing words on peace?
>> Yes. I just like to um say that it's
it's an awareness. You know, just try to
be as
aware as po of as possible of that peace
that we can have and that is available
to all of us
because it really is there. We really
can have it.
>> Amen.
>> Yes. He wants us to experience that
every day.
>> I'll save it for next week, too.
>> Amen.
>> But it's such a beautiful gift God gave
us to be able to have peace in the
middle of a storm because we live in
this world. There's always a storm.
>> Yes. Even if it's
>> true
>> somebody else, you see somebody, even if
you're not in a storm, but you see
somebody else you love in a storm or
that you care about
>> because of that,
>> it's your your storm vicariously through
them. So
>> yes, looking forward to taking a deeper
dive with all of you for next week uh as
we continue the discussion for peace.
want to thank our viewing audience for
participating with us for Sabbath school
and being here with us and sharing your
thoughts definitely helped us um for
this segment. But don't go anywhere
because church is just starting and
we're about to go into the divine
worship. But um like to ask one of our
guests so if we could go back to them
guys and let one of our guests pray us
out. Any one of you can um volunteer to
pray.
Yeah, I'll pray.
>> All right, Kashie. Thank you.
>> Father in heaven, we thank you, Lord,
for first getting rid of the technical
issues that we experience.
>> Amen.
>> Thank you for all the prayers that went
up for that, Lord.
>> And Lord, I just ask you to continue to
keep us in your peace throughout this
Sabbath.
>> Help us to truly keep it holy, Lord.
>> Lord, I ask you to be with our pastor as
he as he prepares to deliver the sermon.
Lord bless each and everyone who is
viewing and who will and who will view
later. Lord, thank you for hearing and
answering our prayer in Jesus name.
Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> And amen.
>> The name of the book is the Christian
Art of War.
>> Yes, guys. Thank you. You can get So, if
you I'm going to in just a few minutes
when we do the welcome for church, I'm
going to show you how to if you're not
on Mighty Networks how to get on that.
And we um have released the first four
chapters. Now, we're going to peace.
That's five. Peace is the thing.
>> No, no, no. We're still in the fourth
chapter. So all
>> Oh, I'm so Okay. Sorry, guys.
>> On chapter four.
>> We're on chapter four. So, the first
four chapters are on mighty network so
that you can get that so you could be
following along with us.
>> Um, yeah. And we don't want you to go
anywhere. Church is happening right now.
You're in church. It's continuing, I
should say. Divine worship is is is
happening in just a moment. Do you want
to share anything about your sermon? So,
uh, the name of the sermon is Rapture
Delusions,
how not to get caught up.
And I'm going to leave it there. Now,
for many of you, you'll be like, "Oh, I
mean, I know where this is going." But I
guarantee you,
>> you don't
>> you don't know where this is going.
Evangelism Sabbath. So, um please be
sure to invite um your friends, family,
etc. And we will uh see you again soon.
>> Yes, in just a few minutes.
>> And definitely share. This is the time
to share. Um you know, we we always say
share, but like and share. If you have
not liked, subscribe, please do so. This
is this will help us as well. But
definitely share on your social media.
Send this link to a family or friend, a
co-orker, and invite them to church, and
we will see you in the divine worship
service. Don't go anywhere.
here. Move to the center. Okay.
battery 32%
Oh, I'm sorry.
Move over a little more T.
You see, what I'm trying to do for my
house today is what Jesus is trying to
do for our lives every single day to
rebuild and repair, restore and raise up
what the enemy arsonist has burnt. Have
you been burnt by someone? Has your
hopes been shattered like glass? Your
dreams reduced to ashes? Well, if so, I
want you to know that today you still
have a reason to smile. For the same God
that created you from the dust can also
recreate the charred ruins of your
broken life. No matter what you're going
through, God's grace is sufficient.
[music]
I'm confident that my family are going
to rebuild and rebound from this
terrible experience. And by the grace of
God, so can you. And so today, I
encourage you to allow God to clear away
the dust of your disappointment. Let God
come into the home of your heart to
begin the rebuilding process. He will
not force himself in. You must open the
door. And if you do, he will give you
the garment of praise for the spirit of
heaviness, the oil of joy for the itch
of mourning, and the beauty of salvation
for the ashes of sin.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat.
Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
>> Heat.
Hey. Hey.
>> [music]
>> Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
>> Welcome back, Living Mana Church family.
I'm so happy that you decided to
continue to worship with us today. We
didn't get to do this in our first uh
service. So, please put in the chat
where you are viewing from. And if this
is your very first time um here at
Living Man Church, we want you to put
where you're viewing from and put a one
in the chat. But we want to say a
special welcome to all of you, but a
very special welcome to those who are
viewing for the very first time. So I'm
excited to see where everyone is viewing
from today. Had a great uh Sabbath
school uh last last session, last
program. Uh today it was a great we you
know we started a little bit late
because of the technical difficulties
but wow did everybody really bring bring
it today like what God was uh sharing
with them to share and it was truly a
blessing. All right so we have uh I
think Christy from South Carolina.
Welcome. Good to see you here. Good to
have you here at Living Man Church. We
have Corey from Barbados.
Welcome. Happy to have you here. We have
uh
uh Ryan, our rain or I'm sorry if I'm
messing that up from Minnesota. Welcome.
Good to see you. Uh we have Atlanta,
Georgia. We have um it looks like Chris
from Warsaw, New York. Welcome uh here
to Living Man Church. We have Jodie, our
board member from Vancouver Island.
Always good to see you here, Jody.
And yes, let's see if I've missed any
because they were they were going up uh
pretty fast, but I think I got everybody
that started putting in the chat. No, I
didn't miss anyone. All right. Well, we
have Jerry from Rochester, New York.
Welcome here to Living Mana Church.
Always good to see you. Ayanna Trinidad
and Tobago.
Welcome to church today. Good to see all
of you. Crystal, so good to see you,
Crystal from Spokane, Washington. Always
in our hearts and in our prayers. Uh we
just love your family so much, but it is
very good to see you here, Crystal. And
we are praying for you and uh the kids.
All right, so let's see. We have uh
blessings, joy.
All right. Well, they're just saying
welcome and happy Sabbath. Well, happy
Sabbath to you, too. Um just going to
see some of the others. All right, we
have um from St. Albins, New York, we
have Karen. Welcome. Good to see you
here at Living Mana Church. Always good
to see all of you and from all the
different places that you're viewing
from. I know many of you that are still
viewing from Sabbath School had put in
uh the chat where you were viewing from
and it was from all around the world and
we're so thankful. Always good to see
you, Zadina from my hometown of Pastor
Robels, California and one of our dear
sisters and church member um a previous
church members but always a dear sister
and we love you dearly. All right, we um
have um Utica New York. I you could I
think I I know I said that wrong but
it's good to have you here Ruben from
New York. Um and Stephanie from Bise.
Welcome. Good to have you here. Always
good to have all of you here at Living
Mana Church. Let me tell you how you can
stay connected to Living Mana Church,
how we can stay connected to you. So,
the way that you're going to be able to
do that is to sign up to get text
alerts. And so, you can see there on
your screen, um, you can text LMLC to
number there. And it's so good to do
that because you will be reminded when
we go live throughout the week, we will
send you like 20 minutes before we go
live uh for mental health Mondays, true
health Tuesdays, before our prayer
services, which we have two prayer
services on Wednesday uh for Pastor
Lami's programming which he's starting a
new program that's going to be I believe
it starts at the beginning of November
on Thursdays. And so you will get 20
minutes notice in advance to remind you
that we are going live. So, it's always
extremely helpful if you're like me and
your life is very, very busy. And even
though you have good intentions to do so
many different things because life is
always lifing, it's nice to get those
text alerts that remind us of things
that um that are happening with church
and that we are wanting to attend. So,
that only works if you are here in North
America. If you are outside of North
America, you don't get the text alerts.
So, you're going to want to sign up for
Mighty Networks. If you have not signed
up for Mighty Networks, that is where
you're going to get your updates. And
really, all of us should be a part of
Mighty Networks. No matter if we are in
North America or outside of North
America, because this is our virtual
church home. This is where uh we
connect. You get to meet people. you um
get to learn about all of our small
groups. You get to learn or meet, I
should say, the leaders and there's so
many things going on in Mighty Network.
So, you're definitely going to want to
sign up for Mighty Networks. And the
link to do that is in the chat. So,
please uh click on that link and sign up
for Mighty Network so you can stay
connected to Living Mana Church. Also
want to remind everyone that we do have
children's programming and that's LMOC
Kids and Lamosci Kids has been such a
blessing to our young children. We have
great leadership and they meet at 11:30
central uh central time and you have to
text kids to that 855 number or email uh
to the email that you see there on your
screen. And as you know we no longer use
Alterive. though that graphic is not
quite correct but um there is another
space where LLC kids meets and I believe
it's a zoom link uh that you will get
once you register your children for LMOC
kids but we are thankful um to have
children's programming here at Living
Mana Church. So if you're interested in
getting your child involved grand uh
grandchild or a niece or a nephew or you
wanted to share that information with a
friend, please do so. the children would
be very blessed to come and participate
in Elosi Kids. Also want to remind you
guys about uh Pastor Meyer's virtual
office hours. If you need to talk to the
pastor because he's your pastor, you can
set up a time to meet with him virtually
by emailing patrice livingmana.live.
That's the best way to be able to set up
a virtual office hour meeting with
Pastor Meyers. Also, um if you're
wanting to transfer your membership, you
saw at the beginning of Sabbath School,
we um transferred there was two
membership transfers. If you are wanting
to do that, you can also use that same
email patrice at living.live.
Also, if you are already, if you want to
join the church and you are not 7th Day
Adventist, but you um have been studying
and you believe everything that Seventh
Day Adventists believe from the Bible,
you can transfer. I'm sorry, not
transfer. You can join by profession of
faith uh because you've already been
baptized before and you don't feel like
you need to be rebaptized, but you would
like to become a member of the 7th Day
Adventist Church, specifically LMLC, you
can use that same email uh to at
patricemana.live.
If you would like to be baptized, then
you can also join the church that way
and Pastor Meyers will do your baptism.
and we are having a baptism on November
15th. So, we are excited about that.
Also, just wanted to let you guys know
and you're not going to see a graphic
here, but just to remind you that we do
have Mental Health Monday is back and we
are in our third, I believe third
program, third program for this fourth
season and Dr. White and myself are
going to be hosting. Um we are the host
of Mental Health Monday and we are going
to do part two. We started a series on
marriage and we want you guys to bring
your questions um about marriage and
relationships. We had a lot of fun last
Monday. We had a lot of singles come by
and they had a lot of questions. So
we're asking answering questions for
singles as well. Uh we had we had a lot
of fun. So you have to come check it
out. That's Monday at uh 700 p.m.
Central time. So,
put that um on your calendar. But even
if you have to be reminded, you will get
a text alert and be reminded of when we
go live. Also want to remind you of
communion that is coming up this Friday,
October 31st. We will have a communion
service at 700 p.m. Central time. So,
please scan that QR code. If you have
not uh ordered your communion bread or
your communion juice, you can do that by
scanning the QR code. And you will also
be able to see where you can order it
from, but also on how to make your own
communion bread um as well. So, you will
have options. You will have options
there. So, communion is this coming
Friday, October 31st at 700 p.m. Central
time. and we're looking forward uh to
having communion as a church family. Um
it has always been a blessing when we
have communion here at Living Mana
Church. Want to also remind you guys
about hangouts. Um hangouts
and this last hangouts we had was this
past Sunday and it's really a lot of fun
to be able to connect and to meet
everybody and get to hear man I'm
learning a whole lot about people that I
did not know. So, it's a lot of fun and
that it hangouts is just what it sounds
like. We're hanging out. But this one,
Hangouts at LMLC is having its first
ever wa watch party for the whole month
of November. We are previewing the
latest uh season of the thrilling series
House of David. We'll watch the show
together and afterwards we'll share our
insights, critiques as a hangout crew.
We worship together. Let's watch House
of David together. Text Hangouts to the
855207-4107
that you see there on your screen for
reminders so you don't miss the show.
You can also scan the QR code to join
the hangout space on Mighty Network. So,
that is going to be a lot of fun. So,
you're not going to want to miss that.
Also just want to remind you guys about
Elosi Global.
Elosi Global we um is a technology that
allows us to be able to go about to
translate Pastor Meyer's messages into
seven different languages. And if you're
not familiar with it, I want to give you
just an example of what that looks like.
[music] Absolute
revolution.
[music]
Gloria
Gloros
[music]
Gloria Jesus [music]
glorific. Arusia
[music]
Gloria.
>> [music]
>> If you would like to help us continue to
be able to translate in more languages
and support Living Mana Global, you can
do that by going to Advent
Adventistgiving
uh.org. And I just want to thank you um
from our our church leadership uh that
we are so uh thankful for what you have
done um here at Living Man Church and
supporting uh the mission to go into all
the world and now we're trying to also
go into eventually all the languages of
the world. Right now we can go in seven
and we want to grow that to be able to
go into more. And so the way that you
can give to support Living Mana Church
um in all the different areas, LMLC
Global and the other areas is to go to
Adventistgiving.org.
There you will put in living mana church
and you will find uh a virtual tithe
envelope. There you can give your tithe
which goes to support the northeastern
conference which Living Matter Church is
a member and a church in that
conference. Also, you can give to the
local church budget. That helps to
support what Living Manage Church is
doing. Um, all the things that you see
that we are doing, all the technical
things that we have to have to be able
to go live and be 100% online, that all
comes from our our local church budget.
So, to help us stay online and to into
all the world, you give to the local
church budget. Um, and you also have
many other things there on the uh tithe
envelope where you can give and support
that. We have our benevolence fund which
we had our leader of the benevolence uh
fund on last week and you were able to
hear some of the the things that the
benevolence fund is in ways that it's
helping uh those who are currently in
need. And so you're able to give there
as well. And you will see when you go to
adventgiving.org or all the other areas
that you can where you can give. If
you're not wanting to give virtually,
you can also mail in your tithe and
offering. And there's the address, PO
Box 428, Owens Crossroads, Alabama
35763.
Please put a note um in your uh in your
envelope to let us know where you want
uh your funds to go. How much is for
tithe? How much is for offering? If
you're wanting to give to the
benevolence fund or to something else,
so we will know where your funds should
go to. And that is how you can give to
Living Mana Church. And we again, we
just want to say thank you. We're so
thankful for all your faithfulness. We
have been here. We're definitely three
and a half years old. And in April, we
will be four years old. And so we are
just so thankful for all of your
support, your financial support, your
prayers, again, how you share uh to
others about Living Mana Church. All of
you are just such a blessing. We just
want to give God the praise right now
for all that he has done uh in our lives
and for this church. So if you would
please just bow your heads with me as we
pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, I just thank you
for this Sabbath. Lord, I thank you and
I praise you uh for just what you have
done. Lord, I thank you for our
broadcast team that worked really hard.
I know that was a stressful hour to just
get us live. But Lord, through you and
through your strength, Lord, you helped
them and we are live and we are just so
thankful for that. Lord, I just want to
lift up all the prayer requests, Lord,
of everyone who is watching. Lord, I
don't know their specific requests, but
I know there are needs for family, for
marriages, for health, for finances.
Lord, you know their heart. You know
what they are praying about. And I am
asking that you would answer their
prayers, Lord, according to your will.
But Lord, they're crying out to you and
they are needing your assistance in so
many different areas. So Lord, please uh
do what you do uh for all of us, Lord,
and answer those prayers for them. Lord,
I'm just going to lift up Pastor Meyers
at this time. Just praying that the Holy
Spirit, the one who gave him today's
message, will uh speak to us, speak
through him and speak through him to our
hearts so that we will want to make the
changes in our lives that is needed. We
ask all these things in Jesus name.
Amen.
I keep fighting [music] voices in my
mind that say I'm not [singing] enough.
Every single [music] lie that tells me I
will [singing] never measure up.
>> Am [music and singing] I more than just
the sum of every high and every
[singing] low? [music]
Remind [music]
me once again just who I [singing] am
because I need to know.
>> You [singing] say I am loved
when I can't feel a thing.
You say I [singing] am strong
when I think I am weak.
And you say I am held
when I am falling short. [singing]
And when I don't belong.
Oh, you say I am yours [singing]
and I believe.
Oh, I [singing] believe
what you say of me.
I believe
>> the only thing that matters
[singing and music] now is everything
you think of me.
Oh,
>> in [singing and music] you I find my
worth. In you I find my [singing]
identity.
Oh,
you say I am lost when I can't feel a
thing.
You say I [singing] am strong [music]
and I think I am weak.
You say I [singing and music] am held
when I am falling short.
When I don't [music] belong.
You say I am yours
and I believe. Oh. Oh. I believe
what you [singing and music] say of me.
I believe
[music]
[singing] came down and set me free. I
am yours.
I am [singing] forever yours.
Mountains [music] higher, valley low, I
sing, [singing]
remind my soul that I am yours.
I am forever yours. You [singing] say I
am loved.
When I can't feel [music] a thing,
you say I am strong.
[music] When I think I am weak.
You say I am hell
and I [music and singing] am falling
short.
And when I don't belong.
Oh, you say I [singing] am yours.
And I am yours.
[music] I am yours.
All my days,
Jesus. I [music] am yours.
I [singing] am yours.
I am yours
from all my days.
Jesus, I am yours
and I believe. [singing]
Oh, I believe
what you say [singing]
of me.
I believe.
Here at Living Mana, we bear [music]
each other's burdens. When you need
support or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged [music]
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face [music] life
struggles alone.
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
[music] grace that we may obtain mercy
and find grace to help in our time of
need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those [music] who are crushed
in spirit.
Amen. Amen. Amen. And greetings, saints
of the most high God. Good to see you
all today. Happy Sabbath. I'm brother
Terry as always here with my lovely
bride Amra. So happy to be with you and
to be able to serve you today in this
great capacity. Uh those of you who are
just joining us, welcome to LMOC. Hope
that this will be a blessing for you
today.
We started off the day pretty uh I won't
say rocky, but uh it was uh it was it
was it was challenging in some ways, but
we are thankful. We're rejoicing. It was
good to see some of y'all in the chat
>> playing fruit of the spirit, right? They
had a little game going and I just
jumped in there and threw a wrench in
the middle of said, "Hey, today we're
talking about patience." We weren't. So,
uh
hopefully we can still be rejoicing in
spite of all that stuff, you know. And
so, uh, man, just giving y'all giving
God praise today. Love y'all. Want to
send a shout out to my brother Leon
Riley. Love you, my man. Miss you. Uh,
looking forward to seeing you sometime,
bro. Let's Let's hook up. And the rest
of the Saints in the chat family, we
love y'all. Um, I wanted to send a
special shout out to Sister Tanya,
>> Sister Tanya Lozano. Yes, we love you,
our beloved sister. She is the leader of
the children's ministry here at Loc. Uh
thank you for all reaching out and
checking in on us and checking on Amra
and I know that you guys been kind of
connecting a little bit. So uh love you
sister Tanya and we thank you for all
the work that you do and all those who
surround you and work along beside you
there. We we do love you and cherish you
here. I wanted to also send uh another
shout out to Sister Charlotte. I don't
know if you're watching today, but we
love you. We haven't forgotten about
you. And uh Sister Ramona, I see you in
the chat. God bless you today. Happy
Sabbath.
>> Amen. Um, just everybody. I see y'all.
Hellos's to y'all.
>> Aiana, Laya, we love you, too.
>> All right. Don't forget my girl
Christiey's in South Carolina, my home,
my neck of the woods. Love you,
Christie. And um Wendy's here.
>> Thank you, Wendy.
>> Amen. Everybody, we are thankful to be
uh on this side of the storm. And uh
it's been good, right? God has been
God's been good.
>> I've missed you the last two weeks. I
know you were here two weeks ago. I was
recovering from
>> another kidney procedure, but I feel
really good and I will be going through
some testing on November 12th. So, keep
me in prayer.
>> Amen.
>> That will determine if we have to
continue on this journey for a little
while longer or if the journey is done
and I'm officially on my healing
journey. So, November 12th is kind of a
big testing day. And then last weekend
we had to attend a funeral for another
friend of mine who passed from cancer.
So we're just grateful to be back. So
>> Amen. Amen. And listen, first lady said
something today. I just can't let it go.
Pre- praise. Praise him in advance.
>> Amen.
>> Praise him in advance, saints. Let's
let's start getting our pre- praise on.
Uh the women of LMOC have been helping
us out to do that a lot with especially
uh Sister P and Sister Joanne did that
powerful praise power Wednesday. Oh man,
so awesome. So awesome that we got a
chance to praise the Lord together. So
pre- praise. Pre- praise everybody. And
sister Jackie, you know I love you and
brother Danny. Y'all be doing the the
thing. They brought the fire this
morning. Gave us something to praise God
about. A good word. Thank God for
Brother Danny and Sister Jackie. They
are uh just a blessing to us and arms to
shoulders to lean on when we need help
and always willing to stand up and serve
the Lord. And I'm gonna tell you, Jackie
and Danny, listen, ever since they've
come, brought a ball of fire and energy
to us that we've needed. So, pre praise.
Pre praise. Who is this?
Thank you so much. Thank you. I don't
know who is it.
>> Rain.
>> Rain. Yes.
>> Rain Moon Unit.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Rain. We love you.
Thank you for your continued prayers.
We're going to continue to pray for you
all, too.
>> And we love you, too, Zadwa. Thank you,
>> Sister Zadwa. Definitely. Much love to
you.
>> And I We said Ayanna already, right?
>> We'll say it again.
Love you. Love you. Listen, I want to
say something earlier. Somebody Somebody
said they heard some sound in here that
was kind of feeding back and I want to
apologize for that. Uh we had to change
our floors out and we uh I moved the
fish tank into the studio and it was a
little bubbling back there bubbling
gurgling
>> in the background. So
>> I just told the brother say y'all hold
your breath for a minute. No, I just
turned it off so it won't make all that
noise but they'll be fine. They'll be
fine. And so my beloved, what do we have
for praise reports? I believe that's
everything today. Everybody we wanted to
shout out.
>> Yes. Yes. So before I go into the praise
reports, just a reminder that if you
have a prayer request or a praise report
that you would like to submit,
please send an email to praymanana.urch.
If you would like to join the prayer
team, we are always looking for members
to join us and be a part of this amazing
community. Also, same email address,
praymmanana.urch.
>> Amen.
>> If you would uh like to request a
special ops team for you or your loved
one, special ops teams are targeted
prayer teams that pray um multiple times
a week, sometimes every day um for
specific need. Please send an email to
spec ops. That's s pops
livingmana.urch.
If you would like to join the women's
ministry on mighty networks, please send
an email to women livingmana.urch.
And finally,
if you would like to join the men's
ministry, please send an email to men
livingmana.urch.
And just note, the men's ministry has a
new email address. It used to be seven
loaves, but it is now much easier men at
living men adoption.
>> All right, then. [laughter]
Yes.
Yes. Yes.
>> Yes.
>> I kind of like the seven lows, but men
men's easier to remember.
>> It's a lot easier. Men, seven lows. I
mean,
>> and there's there's there's something I
want I saw in the chat. I wanted to
reach out and say, "Brother Leon just
asked for prayers for Jamaica that's in
the eye of the storm. We definitely want
to keep Jamaica in our prayers, beloved.
We will be doing that today. And also
Trinidad and Tobago. You know,
historically, US already has a presence
there uh in the port of Spain. But one
of our destroyers is moving in going to
visit that port tomorrow. I believe
it'll be pulling in there and because
there's been a a recent increase of US
military presence there due to due to
some things going on between the US and
uh Venezuela. So we uh we want to um Is
it Venezuela? Yes. So we want to uh keep
both in prayer. You know, some of our
brothers and sisters, they're a little
on edge about what's going on. But
>> yeah, we have a lot of very beloved
church members, family
>> in the Caribbean. Yes. Yes. Particularly
in Trinidad and Tobago, many of our
brothers and sisters. And so we want to
uh keep them in prayer that that none of
this will steal their joy. Hold on to
your joy, saints. God is good. And uh
but particularly in the eye of that
storm because there's there's a lot of
unrest because of that. But God God can
keep and he cannot protect.
>> Yes, ma'am. Yes, ma'am.
>> All right.
Artell Peters starts us off with two
praise reports. The first one being, I
want to share the blessings that Jesus
has revealed to me. a shared yoke with
him on his promise of light lighting my
p light lightening my perceived burden
by taking up his yoke of mercy. I am
thankful to listening for answers to
prayers of expectation of his choosing
when I'm allowed for my desire to align
with God's will. The unfolding choices
of my Bible study partner Nathaniel has
been given the choice of not just a job
but for the first time having the view
of working or not working on the seventh
day Sabbath or to choose working on the
first day Sunday of the sun god. I am
privileged to be part of a spiritual
awakening for me being given to witness
on my choices that led us both to a
point of the freedom to choose God over
um job for material satisfaction. I pray
for Nathaniel's discernment. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Praise number two.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> God is good all the time and all the
time God is good. Well, yes, he is.
Absolutely.
When I asked for God to put people in my
path so that I may focus on others, he
did. I became a part of my Bible study
partner Mathaniel Parker's shared
responsibility in viewing his living
unhoused on the streets that it took my
focus
on my own cancer surgery and healing.
The early discovery didn't allow for it
to manifest before being removed through
a robotic procedure. And as a result,
yesterday's doctor's visit revealed less
than a 0% of my previous PSA levels to
be studied moving forward.
>> Praise God.
>> I do believe God sent Nathaniel as a
mirror for my own condition to be viewed
through the condition of others. Praise
God.
>> Artill, that's a major praise report. My
>> that is huge huge
>> major major victory
>> from Tequila. Thank you all for praying
for me to pass my CNA test. Praise
report. I passed. Praise God. And scored
very high on the test. Amen.
>> I am now a certified nursing assistant.
>> Come on, somebody. Praise God for that.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Congratulations, Tequila.
>> We're rejoicing with you.
>> Amanda, thank you all for praying for me
to get a job. Praise report. I was hired
as a certified peer recovery specialist
at the Davidson County Mental Health and
Veteran Treatment Court.
>> Praise God. Praise God.
>> Amen. Congratulations to you, too,
Amanda.
>> Yeah. What an amazing area to work, too.
That's that's that's great.
>> Very, very cool.
From Pauline, thank you for praying for
me, family. The VA released the funds
and I received my paycheck. Praise
Almighty God who said in his word, "Our
bread and water is assured. Glory to
God."
>> Amen. Amen. Rejoicing, Sister P.
>> Yes. I think this one was caught in the
chat. It was just sent to me from Jamie.
Praise God for his grace and healing
power in my mom's health and daughter's
conversion.
And then finally from Francis Grant, I
want to give an update on my husband
Nigel. In my original prayer request, I
asked for prayer for my husband who was
in the hospital with serious health
issues. I was grateful and thankful that
the Lord had spared his life twice. When
it looked as though all was lost, I had
asked the prayer family to keep him in
prayer that the Lord's will be done.
Following discharge from the hospital,
my husband was sent to a rehab facility.
At the time he was admitted, he was
unable to talk, barely could eat, and
was unable to get out of bed.
>> Please understand that no one on the
medical team expected him to be able to
do anything going forward because of the
severity of his health conditions. But
God had a plan.
>> Amen. I praise the Lord for his goodness
and mercies because now my husband is
able to talk and has been upgraded from
a puree diet to a regular chopped food.
Has been standing with assistance, able
to push very slowly on his own, his
wheelchair.
God is beyond awesome. His wonders to
perform. Our God is more than able to do
exceedingly abundantly beyond all that
we can think or imagine. Hallelujah.
Hallelujah. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Thank you all for your prayers. I will
continue to keep you aware of his
progress as the Lord does his perfect
will. Also, I had asked for prayer for a
family friend, Marcus, who needed to
move and to pass the test of his black
seal license. By the grace of God,
Marcus has moved into a place he can
afford yesterday.
>> Praise God. Praise God. Come on,
>> Francis. Wow.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Wow. as you were reading
that and all the hallelujah were coming
out like look I'd sure like to be
present with Francis as she giving this
testimony because I can tell you there
was some shouting going on there. So
thank God for the praise reports and
listen everything in its time and in its
season. Your season's coming. Our God is
no respector of persons. When you read
that, take it to heart and rejoice
knowing, hey, look, you can be patient
in the waiting knowing that your season
is coming. And God has a purpose for
each of our lives and he's not going to
keep you in that storm any longer than
it is required to fulfill his plan and
purpose for you. And so be encouraged
saints today. Continue to wait. Continue
to pray. Continue to uh pre- praise.
Start praising now before the answer
comes. Start praising now. You know,
some of us, I think, I know it's been
the case with me in the past and and
that that if I'm not in the right
attitude, my blessing could just go
flying right past me while I'm in that
little bad attitude. Right. So, we want
to be we want to be ready to receive.
Right.
>> Can I share the little nugget I heard
this morning?
>> Yes. Oh, that. Yes.
>> Wasn't that great? Okay. So, yes. So I
heard I was listening to a little Bible
study and it was on waiting and you know
patience will be the next
[clears throat]
Sabbath school I believe right
>> peace and then it'll come. Yeah.
>> Okay. Well, I guess I need to be patient
for patience. But as we're waiting on
our blessing and sometimes we can feel
like we're in the darkness or we're
overlooked or where is God? I'm not
hearing him.
>> And I heard this today that sometimes
when we're in the soil,
the soil is not the grave, it's the
womb. So, as seeds are being planted, as
the Lord plants us in a season of
darkness, in a season of waiting, in a
season of quietness, he's strengthening
our character. He's building us up.
>> He is giving us his light.
>> Amen. through that ground and when the
time is right and when the seed is
ready,
>> yes,
>> it bursts through the the soil and uh it
manifests into the fruit. So,
>> hold on. Hold on.
The blessing is coming. The soil is not
the grave. It is the womb. I liked that.
I like that.
>> Be still in there.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. All right. Be still somebody.
>> The silence is just God working on the
miracle.
>> Well, amen. Praise God. Somebody
[laughter] needed to hear that watching
today. Somebody needed to hear that to
be encouraged. And so, saints, we're
getting ready to go to the throne of
grace again to water some of those seeds
you have been uh holding on to and
you've been watching and you've been
waiting for your time. when we want to
continue here at Living Mana, we put uh
uh we take Ve very prayer very seriously
and we thank God for the privilege and
honor of being prayer warriors, of
standing in the gap and and being
mindful of us, calling us, allowing us
to be co-ors together with him. So, as
we get ready to go to the throne of
grace today, we have special prayer
warriors, our very own motheraughter duo
team. Now uh sister Dolores here of
Shaunin who just joined the prayer
ministry and we are super super honored
to have sister Dolores but let me first
of all let me introduce a little bit
about it's not like y'all don't know
Shaine right but I got to tell you
something about this sister here I mean
sisters have been faithfully serving
with us from the beginning she is a
prayer warrior a warette I mean she's a
part of give mana she's a part of the
prayer team of course she's a prayer
team leadership uh she has worked to
create our LOC business digital business
directory. That's going to be a powerful
blessing for those who have businesses
at LOC. She does a lot of special
programming, some of the holiday
programming we see and plays even. I
believe she's working to put together
the communion service that we just heard
the first lady announce about. And you
know what? There's other other things
she does. She does a lot. But I do want
to say one thing she does that's really
important to me. She is our fourhour
phone conversationalist,
right? She keep me on the phone. Wow.
Encouraging me.
>> Does she keep you on the phone or you
keep her on the phone?
>> Something like that. One or the other.
But we're on the phone and I'm being
encouraged by my beloved and beautiful
sister. [laughter]
>> We I can hear you. So, um just want to
say hello and um just want to praise God
for being here. I don't know what you've
already said, brother Terry, but I see
you're laughing, so I know you you did
something. I'll get you later.
[laughter] Okay. But I'd like to
introduce my mom. I have a little prayer
here myself. I was praying for my mom.
Um to um just just so a ministry that we
could do together. And um when Sister
Dot and Pauline were here, she started
praying with us. And we all like, "You
need to be on the prayer team." and she
was like, "Oh, I don't know. I'm a
little shy. I don't know if I can if I
can do that." And we were like, "Yes,
you can do this." And so, here she is.
This is her first time um being live.
So, she said she's a little nervous like
she's okay. So, I've been praying all
the time. I wouldn't be here if it
weren't for the prayers of my mom. So at
any age and mom is 90 almost 91 years
young and [clears throat] uh so she's
been praying a long time for me and so
here I am. [laughter] Praise God.
So I will open and
mom.
>> Okay. So I'm going to take my glass off.
All righty. So
first I'd like to say just uh dear
heavenly father I just want to thank you
so much. uh you knew that we would be
here um mom and daughter um just
praising you and this wonderful um
online church experience that we have
been having and I just want to praise
you for it and just thank you so much
Lord. No matter how old young or old you
are as we sort from Sabbath school um at
all ages we can praise and serve until
we take our last breath. And so we just
thank you, Lord, for um just for the
power of prayer. And this is living
proof right here of the power of your
word and the power of your promise as we
go to your throne of grace. Lord, I just
pray that you will just pour out a
blessing on each and everyone that we
bring before your throne of grace as we
come boldly as [clears throat] you have
promised. I pray that you will forgive
us of our sins, Lord. Help us to
overcome them, Father. And I just ask
Lord that you put the right words in my
heart, in our mouths, and so that we
will speak what you want your children
to hear. And Father, I pray that you
will open the hearts of everyone who is
listening and those who will listen
later, Lord, that they know that there
is power and there is always hope if we
just trust in you. So my first prayer,
Lord, is that you just pour out your
Holy Spirit upon each of us. I ask
father that you um continue to pour out
give us faith and wisdom. Help us to
trust you especially in these last days.
We see so many things people running to
and fro but not us Lord because we are
grounded Lord but sometimes we know not
shouldn't say sometimes we know Satan is
always assailing us and as brother Terry
said we are not under attack we are over
and we are here because we are coming to
your throne and we know the power and so
Lord um first I want to bring um JMA is
saying, "Please continue to pray for
Tammy and her young daughters. She has
found temporary housing. Pray for her to
for her faith and her continued um uh
just her continued blessings, Lord, and
strength [clears throat] in Jesus
Christ." Amen. We are just continuing to
pray for us uh Sister Tammy, and we just
thank you. And um we also are lifting up
the people in Jamaica. We know that
there is going to be a direct uh hit
according to the weather report, but we
don't know what God has in store. So,
like I say, according to the weather
reports. So, mom is going to pray for uh
that situation. Okay. Dear father, we do
thank you for the privilege of being
able to be come before your throne of
grace. Father, you know the beginning
from the end. We pray that you'll
remember the people and your children,
all them that are in Jamaica. We know
that the th the storm is threatening
them, but thou art the creator of all
things and thou art able to control what
happens there. We pray that you will
give them
peace and [clears throat] safety, Lord,
so that the the uh so that the storm
will not impact them so negatively.
We pray that they will have a testimony
after it passes of how you took care of
them. We pray for the other young people
who uh o who my daughter just alluded
to. Father, you know their situation.
You know what their their needs are. We
pray that you will take care of them
according to your will. And we thank you
for the answered prayers that we know
that you will do. And we thank you in
Jesus most precious name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Amen.
And um Jamie is saying is asking please
pray please pray for Eddie his sister
Trion just passed this week. She was a
dear sweet sister in Christ and praise
the Lord for that. Praise the Lord that
she was fell asleep in the Lord. And we
do pray for um Lord, we just lift up um
Eddie and his their whole family. Lord,
we know that we do grieve, but we don't
grieve as others grieve when we know
what we know about your your the
resurrection. Lord, we know that you are
coming back for us and that it just a
little wild that we will see you again.
So those who sleep will be awakened by
your voice and caught up in the air and
there we will all live with you forever.
So this is our hope Lord and we just
praise you and you we thank you and
please comfort Eddie and his family with
the remembrance of this. We pray in
Jesus' name.
And mom's going to pray for the wealthy.
>> Dear father,
you know who they are
and and the so many blessings that you
have given them that they have the
wealth. We pray that they will open
their hearts so that they will share
with others that in need. Father, we ask
this blessing also for those who are in
need that they will receive what they
need to be safe and peaceful. And we ask
these blessings in Jesus precious name
also. Amen.
>> Amen.
And Jim
Jamie is also asking, "Please pray for
my sister Karen for her healing and for
her relationship with Jesus Christ to be
stronger." Um, Peterson is asking, "We
need to pray for the person who is
saying unkind things in the shed. They
too need Jesus." Yes, that is true. Um,
Trevor is asking said, "Please help me."
God knows what that is. Uh please play
pray for our continuation to do God's
will and for
Ash Tasha and Dawn's family to come to
fully know God. U pray for brother Taj
and his family ministry. Amen. Please
pray for my family having a lot of
trouble in the house. And that is from
Trevor again. and art. Brother Artell is
praying. My prayers for an appeal
for brother Taj to rebuild would be for
everyone who views his video to send him
$1, if not more, like just $1 for the
reser res uh restoration.
Uh brother Reed W is uh please pray.
Please pray for my good friend Warren
and my friend Frank's family. Orman had
a seizure this week and we don't know
why. Frank's youngest lost his wife to a
25year battle with addiction. The family
is suffering and God please um uh Zadina
pre please pray for strength
that that comes from God from Jesus from
temptation to sin from addiction. I pray
for peace after refusing the temptation.
Amen. Praise God that she was able to
get over that temptation. I am asking
you all to pray for us in Jamaica as
we're facing a terrible hurricane which
we just did. So yes, we're going to
bring all of these prayers to God. And
those of you who we did I did not
mention our prayer team is praying all
through the week, continue to put your
prayers in the chat and we will be
praying over them. So Lord, we just
bring all of these requests to your
throne of grace. Lord, Father, you know,
each and everyone, you know, those who
are grieving, you know, those who are in
need of um financial help. And Father,
we pray for our children. We pray for
our loved ones and our friends who are
going through so many different attacks,
addiction, Lord. Uh many are suffering
from from loss of jobs. Many are
suffering um just from being attacked um
even after like the sister said that
after she got over the temptation she is
praying for strength. So Lord we please
we just pour out your holy spirit and
strengthen each and every one of us Lord
through our trials father. And Lord, we
know that you will never leave us or
forsake us because this is your word and
we we are counting on you. We know that
your word is true and that you are
faithful. So Lord, help us to be
faithful as we come together, Lord, in
one accord to pray in behalf of each and
every one of these um requests. We also
lift up our our min our pastor today and
the message that he is bringing forth to
you Lord and we pray for the technology
to work well Lord and that everyone who
hears this that you would just open
their hearts our hearts to hear and to
listen to what you have to say Lord and
that everyone will be continue I have to
say continue to be blessed because you
have blessed us so much and we just
thank you father for all that you have
done and all that you are going to do
and we present these blessings to you in
Jesus holy name. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> [music]
>> There is [singing] power
in the name of Jesus. [music]
There is power
in the name of Jesus
to break [music] every chain. Break
every chain. Break every chain.
Break [music] every chain. Break every
chain. Break every chain.
>> [music]
>> There is power
in the name of Jesus.
[music] There is power [singing]
in the name of Jesus. [music]
There is power [singing]
in the name of Jesus
to break every [music] chain. Break
every chain. Break every chain.
To break [music] every chain. Break
All sufficient [music and singing]
sacriice.
So [singing] freely
given [music]
such a price for our [singing]
redemption. [music]
Heaven's
gates swing wide. [music]
Oh sicient [music]
[singing] sacriice.
So freely [singing]
gi [music]
such a prize [singing] bought our
redemption. [music]
Heaven's [singing]
gates swing wide.
[music]
There is power
in the name of Jesus.
[singing and music]
There is power
in the [music] name of Jesus.
[singing]
There is power
in the name of Jesus [music and singing]
to break every chain. Break [music]
every chain. Break every chain.
To break every chain.
[music and singing] Break every chain.
Break every chain.
Oh, there is power
in the name [music and singing] of
Jesus.
There is power
in the name of Jesus. [singing]
There is [music] power
in the name of Jesus [singing]
to break [music] every chain. Break
every chain. [singing] Break every
chain.
To break every chain. [music]
Break every [singing] chain. Break every
chain.
Yeah.
[singing]
>> [music]
>> Oh, there's power in your name, Lord.
[music] There's power in your name to
break every chain.
[music]
There's an [singing] army
rising
up.
There's [music and singing] an army
rising
up.
Yes, [music] there's an army
rising [singing] up
to break every chain. [music] Break
every chain. Break every chain.
There's [music and singing] an army
rising
up.
There's an army [music and singing]
rising
up.
Oh, there's an army [singing]
rising
up
to break every chain. Break every
[music] chain. Break every chain.
Oh, [singing]
to break [music] every chain. Break
every chain. Break every chain.
There is power [music and singing]
in the name of Jesus.
There is [music and singing] power
Oh, there is [singing and music] power
in the name of Jesus.
to break every chain. Break every chain.
Break every chain. [singing]
I want to [music] break every chain.
Break every chain. Break every chain.
[singing]
To break every chain. Break every chain.
[singing] Break every chain.
To break every chain. Break every
[music and singing] chain. Break every
chain.
To break every [music] chain. Break
every chain. Break every chain.
To break [music] every chain. Break
Happy Sabbath everyone. Um, welcome to
Living Manor online church. This is the
divine service and it is time for the
message.
Um, please, if you haven't, make sure
that you uh like, make sure that you're
subscribed, make sure that you share
because today I'm going to be talking to
you about a subject I've entitled
Rapture
Delusions. Rapture delusions. So you
guys go ahead, [clears throat]
put a one in the chat if you're ready to
get into the word of God today. Um, and
we're going to be addressing some very
uh serious things, some very important
things that uh every Christian needs to
listen to.
You might be saying to yourself, "Hey, I
understand about the rapture and and so
I'm familiar with this message, but I
need you to lay that to the side and I
need you to lock in on what I'm going to
share today." So, with that said, let's
pray and then we're going to open up in
the message. Heavenly Father, please
speak to us today, Lord. Help us
to grasp the word that you have for us
today.
Lord, may our hearts be open. May our
minds be open.
And Lord, help us to be grounded
in the truth. In Jesus name we pray.
Amen. Amen. How many of you put a put a
two in the chat if your plan, your
desire, your hope is to be grounded in
the truth? two in the chat
because that's going to be my appeal. By
the way, my appeal, just so that you
know, right up front, my appeal is going
to be, "Lord, ground me in the truth."
Ground me in the truth. Let's go to the
screen.
Um,
once again, the title of the message is
Rapture
Delusions. Rapture delusions. And
some time ago, couple of uh couple of
weeks ago, actually uh it was in
September
that
the
news picked up on something that began
to go around, which was that the rapture
was supposed to happen on September
23rd,
which
actually happened to be my birthday.
Now, you know what a day for the rapture
to happen. Um,
and I knew it was not going to happen,
but there were
thousands and maybe millions, I'm not
sure, but
thousands of Christians believing
that the rapture was going to take
place.
Um there was a particular pastor who
basically said that God appeared to him
in a dream and told him that the rapture
would take place on the 23rd of
September.
The 23rd of September came and went
and nothing happened. We are still here.
So why did this happen? What was going
on? What was why were so many people
led astray over this teaching?
Well,
we're going to see that the Bible
literally tells us
how
Christ comes again and that if we would
just read the Bible, there would
actually be no need or no cause for
deception. But the problem is that a lot
of people really aren't reading the
Bible. So let me share with you first of
all 1 Thessalonians chapter 4:13 through
16. And um the Bible says here,
"Beloved, beloved, I would not have you
to be ignorant concerning them which are
asleep, that you sorrow not even as
others which have no hope. For if we
believe that Jesus died and rose again,
even so them also which sleep in Jesus
will God bring with him. For this we say
unto you by the word of the Lord, that
we which are alive and remain unto the
coming of the Lord shall not prevent
them which are asleep. For the Lord
himself
shall descend from heaven with a shout,
with the voice of the archangel, and
with the trump of God, and the dead in
Christ shall rise first.
Then we which are alive and remain shall
be caught up together with them in the
clouds to meet the Lord in the air, and
so shall we ever be with the Lord."
>> [clears throat]
>> This verse
is a key verse that describes
how
Jesus comes again.
And I want you to notice uh in verse 16,
the text said, "For the Lord himself,"
I want you to focus on that word himself
just for a moment.
So himself indicates that
he himself
descends. And if it is he himself
that that descends,
then it would be logical that when this
event happens, Jesus will be visible.
Jesus will be seen.
In fact, in Revelation 1:7, the Bible
says, "Behold, he cometh with clouds,
and every eye shall see him, and they
also which pierced him, and all the
kindreds of the earth shall wail because
of him." And so
the Bible tells us that when Jesus
descends, he is descending himself.
And descending himself means that every
[clears throat] eye will see him.
And if every eye sees him, then it is
not a secret or invisible
rapture. Everybody put a one in the chat
if that makes sense so far. This is not
an invisible rapture. This is not an
invisible catching up.
Every eye sees Jesus when this event
happens. And when Jesus comes again, it
is called the second coming of Jesus
Christ. Then that means
that it is not an invisible event that
people just disappear without knowing
what happened. Hey, what's going on?
What's going on? I think the people were
raptured away. No, every eye sees Jesus
so that there is no question
about the event that has taken place.
Again, in Matthew chap 24:36,
the Bible says, "But of that day and
hour, knoweth no man, know not the
angels in heaven, not the angels in
heaven, but my father only. But as the
days of Noah were, so shall also the
coming of the Son of Man be. For as in
the days that were be before the flood,
they were eating and drinking, marrying
and giving in marriage, until the day
Noah entered into the ark, and knew not
until the flood came and took them all
away, so shall also the coming of the
son of man be.
Once again, we see that one of the most
popular verses often used to teach a
secret and invisible rapture actually
describes
[clears throat]
that when Jesus comes again,
those who are not prepared to meet him
will be destroyed.
There is no
um second chance. There is no people
wondering what happened to the people
that disappeared. The text actually says
that when Jesus comes again, it will be
as it was in the days of Noah. And in
the days of Noah, those who were not in
the ark when the door closed were
destroyed.
So there wasn't anything about clothes
left behind and you know, no, no, no,
no, no. they were or airplanes falling
out the sky or you know cars drivers
right John drivers and cars disappearing
nothing like that nothing at all
um it is this same text that talks about
one shall be taken one shall be left and
the context is that
one group of people will be saved and
the other group of people will be
destroyed
Now, that's it, you guys. That That's
it.
That's all I have.
Not all I'm not all that could be
shared, but that's all I have
to share in this message
about this false teaching called the
rapture. Because I want to address
something deeper than this specific
false teaching.
uh because there's a deeper issue at
hand and we're still going to be talking
about the rapture. Don't don't be like I
tuned in here about the rapture. Still
going to be talking about it. But if you
take these verses alone,
these verses alone utterly destroy any
idea of a rapture.
The question then is how is it that
people
are getting
caught up in this false teaching?
How is it that people get caught up in
any false teaching? It's because they're
not reading the Bible for themselves.
It's because they're trusting in others.
And when they hear things that that that
sound good, people tend to get caught up
in things that sound good rather than
what the Bible actually says.
If you're with me so far, again, put a
five in the chat. I want to show you
something because even though what I
just said, uh, I stand by. What if I
told you
that despite the fact that I believe the
Bible uh
definitely shows that the common and
popular teaching of the rapture is in
fact a false teaching? What if I told
you that nonetheless I do believe that
the rapture will happen, that the
rapture is happening, and that the
rapture has happened.
Now,
now,
now I've just thrown everybody off.
those of you that are familiar and those
of you that are maybe hearing me for the
first time or hearing this for the first
time now everybody's off and and that's
why I wanted you to tune in
because what I need you to understand is
that there is something much deeper than
than than why people fall for the false
teaching of the rapture.
Again, what if I told you that the
rapture actually was happening,
has happened, and will happen?
Let me let me break this down for you.
In second Timothy 4:2, the Bible says,
"Preach the word, be instant in season
and out of season. Reprove, rebuke,
resor, exhort with all longsuffering and
doctrine. For the time will come where
they when they will not endure sound
doctrine, but after their own lusts
shall they heap to themselves teachers
having itching ears, and they shall turn
away their ears from the truth, and
shall be turned unto fables.
So the Bible tells us, beloved, that
that a time is coming
and now is [clears throat]
when people have itching ears and they
would rather they would rather believe a
lie or that which sounds good than
actually believing the word of God. Now,
let me say it up front.
There will be a second coming.
Jesus will return and those who believe
in him and trust in him will be caught
up physically, visibly, it will be an
event that will be worldwide.
But the false rapture,
the false doctrine,
the false version of that teaching is
what I'm talking about today. But that
false version extends way beyond
that particular teaching.
Let me go to 2 Timothy chapter 3:1.
Remember, the time will come where
people will not endure sound doctrine,
but will heap to themselves teachers
after their own itching ears. Listen to
what the text says in 2 Timothy chapter
3. This know also that in the last days
perilous time shall come. For men shall
be lovers of their own selves, covetous,
boasters, proud, blasphemers,
disobedient to parents, unthankful,
unholy, without natural affection,
truce, truth breakers, false accusers,
incontinent, fierce, despisers of those
that are good, traitors, heady,
high-minded, lovers of pleasure more
than lovers of God, having a form of
godliness, but denying the power
thereof. From such, turn away. And
here's what I want to focus on right
now, guys. that that phrase lovers of
pleasures.
[clears throat]
Lovers of pleasures.
The Greek word felo hidon broken down
into two two parts. Filelo means to love
or have a deep affection for and hidon
means pleasure. Pleasure.
So a love of pleasure. You say, "Pastor,
what where are you going with this? What
do you mean? Why are you highlighting
love of pleasure?
The word rapture
itself is not found in the Bible. Uh the
word is not found in the English
translation of the Bible. The term is
derived from the Latin rapir in the
Vulgate and it translates to the Greek
word harpazo which means to snatch or
take away and that's what's found in 1
Thessalonians chapter 4:1 17. So when
the text says caught up, right, caught
up, it's it's referring to that Latin
word. And so that's where we get our
English word rapture from, meaning to be
caught up.
However,
there is another meaning for the word
rapture
and it is actually the more popular
meaning of the word. It is a modern
meaning of the word
as related to what was used in the
Bible.
And here's [clears throat] what the word
means in modern terms. And I wish I
could show it to you on the screen, but
um listen to this. The word rapture is a
feeling of intense
pleasure or joy.
So for example, somebody listened with
rapture. It means intense pleasure or
joy. Intense enthusiasm
about something.
So that other definition of the word
rapture means really to be emotionally
caught up.
Y'all put a seven in the chat if you're
following me so far.
The word rapture in its modern sense
means to be emotionally caught up.
Caught up in things that are
pleasurable.
something is pleasurable to the ear or
something is pleasurable to the heart.
One can get caught up in it. Have you
ever heard that's you know man some so
and so got caught up in this or caught
up in that?
It's an intense
dedication
to something that is pleasurable to you.
caught up,
raptured. Could it be possible
that the false teaching of the rapture
is not the only thing
where people run the risk of being
caught up in?
Could it be possible that there are
other people who are getting caught up,
raptured
into other false teachings? Why? Because
they are not grounded
in the word of God.
They would rather itching ears.
They would rather things that that sound
good and feel good to their hearts and
their minds
rather than what the word of God
actually says. And so what happens,
beloved,
[clears throat] is that people begin to
disappear.
That's right, pastor. What do you mean
people begin to disappear? I mean,
senses disappear. Reason disappears when
we get caught up in things that are not
biblical, things that are not true. We
in essence get raptured away. Do you
know anybody that's been raptured?
I want you to think about ho how how
unreasonable
people can be when they get raptured,
when they get caught up in an intense
emotion, lovers of pleasure more than
lovers of God. And so, for example, try
to talk to someone who absolutely
believes in the rapture
that it's going to be invisible, that
it's going to be secret, that there's
going to be a seven-year period left
behind. try to and try to talk to and
it's almost like hey even though I'm
showing them the word and the text and
look at what the scripture says it's you
you can't the senses have gone they've
been raptured
reason raptured
and what I want you to understand
beloved is that the devil doesn't care
how he raptures you just wants to
rapture you
just wants to get you caught up in
something that is not biblical,
something that is not according to the
word of God to get us caught up,
raptured so that the senses disappear.
Are y'all with me so far?
See, now is hitting close to home
because if I ask you again, do you know
people that have been raptured? Let me
tell you something. There are people in
the church that have been raptured. They
have disappeared. They're not the same
person they were four years ago, 6 years
ago, 8 years ago, 10 years ago.
The rapture is happening.
It has happened. It is happening and it
will happen.
And it's an absolutely absolutely crazy
phenomenon.
It not only happens to those who believe
doctrines that are not according to the
Bible, but it happens with those who
believe the Bible, who believe the
doctrines of the Bible, who are still
getting raptured.
Come on, y'all. Put a seven in the chat.
If you can say, "Wow, I know people that
have been caught up.
I know people that have been raptured
and and trying to talk and trying to
reason. It's not there. The reasoning is
not there. The senses aren't there. It's
just caught up in an intense it's an
intense catching up.
And this is a problem, beloved, not only
inside our church, but outside our
church. Or I should say not only outside
our church, but inside our church.
Outside the church, it might be getting
raptured by false doctrines, but inside
the church, it's a whole different set
of raptures happening.
A whole different set of of of c being
caught up going on.
I want to talk to you about the first
person that was raptured, left their
senses, got caught up. Who was the first
person? I'm just going to ask. I'm I'm
gonna ask you to put it in the chat.
Just see if you can tell me who was the
first person, first human being to get
caught up, to get raptured,
to have the senses
disappear, reason disappear. Yes. Yes.
Let's go to Genesis chapter 3.
Genesis chapter 3. Uh, we see that Eve
is in a discussion with the serpent and
she gets caught up. Doesn't she get
caught up? Does she get caught up,
everyone? Does she get caught up in a
false doctrine? Does she get caught up
in a false teaching? Yes, she gets
caught up. If she had just trusted the
word of God and not trusted her senses,
not trusted what she felt was right, not
gone along
with the enemy's twisting of the word,
Eve would have been all right. But the
text says, "When the woman saw that the
tree was good for food, and that it was
pleasant to the eyes, and a tree to be
desired to make one wise, she took of
the fruit and did eat, and gave also
unto her husband with her, and he did
eat.
>> [clears throat]
>> Eve got caught up.
In fact, there's an inspired statement
from the from uh um the first volume of
the of the Spirit of Prophecy, page 37,
which says this. She
ate and was delighted with the fruit. It
seemed delicious to her taste, and she
imagined that she realized in herself
the wonderful effects of the fruit.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Eve was caught up in
rapture.
She was caught up in rapture. She was
caught up in delight. She was caught up
in the love of pleasure more than the
love of God. This thing, this idea was
pleasurable to her. And beloved, what
I'm trying to say is not only what we
see happening in the Christian world at
large today with people getting caught
up with the rapture teaching is that
there they would rather that which
sounds good and that which is popular
and that which movies have been made
after that sounds better than going with
the actual word of God. And the reason
that they get caught up in the false
catching up
is that they
don't
stand on the word of God. Instead, what
they do is they go with emotion. So
remember, rapture is an intense emotion.
That's in in the terms of of the of the
modern definition of the word. It is
being enraptured or caught up in
something. I was enraptured with this
event or that thing or that person. It's
being caught up.
And Eve got caught up.
And let me let me say to you in a very
straightforward way,
the Christian world
is not only by and large being deceived
by false teachings like the rapture, but
they are getting caught up in a whole
bunch of other stuff as well.
being led by intense
emotion,
being involved in in in in movements and
revivals that they are so emotionally
connected to that reason is just gone
out the window.
Bible means nothing. Verses mean
nothing.
People
are getting caught
up.
And here's what I want you to
understand, beloved.
This catching up is not
without
its detriment. I mean, it's detriment.
It's it's it's harmful in and of itself
to be to be to be caught up into false
ideas and false ideologies in the name
of righteousness.
But beloved, those who are caught up
often
get the clothes left behind.
[clears throat]
So you know in the movie right and in
the popular teachings right those who
are raptured their clothes are left
behind.
The clothes are left behind. You just
see clothes on the floor, clothes just
ground.
In the analogy I'm sharing with you
today, and it is an analogy.
I want you to understand that in in in
when you're caught up in false doctrine,
false doctrine typically comes with a
leaving behind
of character. Y'all, you remember? You
remember? Let's go. Let's go back to the
screen. In Genesis 3:7, after they ate
from the tree, the eyes of them both
were open, and they knew that they were
naked,
and they sewed fig leaves together and
made themselves apron. They were naked.
The covering of God was removed from
them, if you will. They were naked. I
want you to notice with me Isaiah 61:10,
where the Bible says, "I will re rejoice
greatly in the Lord. My soul shall be
joyful in my God. For he has clothed me,
clothed me with the garments of
salvation. He has covered me with the
robes of righteousness, as a bridegroom
decketh himself with ornaments, and as a
bride adornneth herself with jewels. I
want you to understand, beloved, that
when when
believers, so-called believers, get
caught up
caught up in false revivals, caught up
in politics, caught up in movements that
sound good,
but are only pleasurable to the sinful
heart. You know what is always left
behind? The righteousness of Christ.
The clothes are left behind.
Righteousness goes out the window in the
name of righteousness.
You understand what I mean? In the name
of righteousness, it is now okay for me
to not have compassion. In the name of
righteousness, it is now okay for me to
not have empathy. In the name of
to to to mock and to rejoice in the fall
of my enemies. I need you to understand
this.
I need you to catch this guys
because this catching up will always be
accompanied by a loss of character, a
loss of the righteousness of Christ.
The Bible says in Galatians 5:19, "Now
the works of the flesh are manifest,
which are these." In other words, this
is what ex this is what is exposed in
these false doctrines and these false
catchings up. Right? In the rapture, you
don't need to be righteous to be caught
up. You just need to be on the right
side to be caught up. That's the
teaching. You don't need to keep the
commandments of God. You don't need to
live holy. As long as you check the
right boxes that you believe this and
you're against this and that and that
and that, you're going to be raptured.
So, you can see how that teaching leaves
aside the righteousness of Christ. But
in the same way, beloved, the same is
true if it's not the rapture teaching.
If it's some other thing that Christians
get caught up in, some conspiracy,
some movement that promises to restore
things in this world the way that they
should be.
Love for neighbor
is mocked.
Love for neighbor, mercy
is downplayed
while allegedly lifting up truth. This
is truth.
Watch this. The works of the flesh,
meaning when you're naked,
this is what is going to happen.
Galatians 5:19. The works of the flesh
are manifest which are these: adultery,
fornication, uncleanness,
lasciviousness, idolatry, witchcraft,
hatred, variance, emulations, wrath,
wrath,
strife, seditions, heresies. You know
what seditions are? Separations,
heresies, envyings, murderers,
drunkenness, revi, reing, and such like
of which I tell you before and have told
you in time past that they which do such
things shall not inherit the kingdom of
God. Now watch this. But the spirit, the
fruit of the spirit is love, joy, peace,
longsuffering, gentleness, goodness,
faith, meekness, temperance. Against
such there is no law. I need you to
understand, beloved,
that people are disappearing.
People in the church are disappearing.
Senses are disappearing. Reason is
disappearing.
The rapture is happening. People are
getting caught up.
It's a false catching up.
It's not the actual catching up to Jesus
when he comes again. It's a catching up
to other ideas and other philosophies.
And so it's a thing. This is why
Revelation 13:11 describes this this
this this counterfeiting, this catching
up, if you will, this this appearing in
the form of godliness, but denying the
power thereof. Revelation 13:11 says, "I
beheld another beast coming up out of
the earth, and he had two horns like a
lamb, and he spake as a dragon." We're
not going to get into what this this
verse is is literally talking about or
symbolically talking about, but I just
want you to look at the principle.
See, a lot of a lot of people get caught
up in looking like Christians,
but in actuality acting like dragons.
Come on, y'all. When I say the rapture
is happening right now, I mean the
rapture is happening right now.
It has happened in the past. It is
happening now. And there is an ultimate
rapture, an ultimate catching up which
is coming at the end of time before
Jesus returns. And if we are not
careful, many will be caught up in that
rapture.
This is why the Bible says in Isaiah
5:20, "Woe unto them that call evil good
and good evil, that put dark that put
darkness for light and light for
darkness, that put bitter for sweet and
sweet for bitter. Woe unto them that are
wise in their own eyes and prudent in
their own sight. Woe unto them that are
mighty to drink wine and men of of men
to mingle strong drink, which justify
the wicked for reward, and take away the
righteousness of the righteous from
him." Beloved, listen to me.
We are living in a time
where wickedness
is being called righteousness
and righteousness is being called
wickedness.
We're living in a time where where
people in the church are defending
certain sins of Satan as if Satan
doesn't traffick in those sins anymore.
We're living in a time where where where
Christians are saying, "Hey, that sin,
oh, that doesn't exist anymore. We've
gotten better since."
Yeah. All these other sins, you could
talk about those, but that sin, oh,
yeah, yeah, yeah, that's not a sin
anymore.
You tell me. You tell me. What sin has
Lucifer let up on?
What sin has Lucifer said, "Ah, you know
what? I'm just not getting the edging
that I used to get with them before. So
maybe I just ought to give up on this
sin."
We don't downplay.
We There are certain sins we don't
downplay,
but other sins we're like, "Oh, yeah.
You know what? That's not a sin anymore.
That's not a sin anymore. Why? Why you
keep Why do you bring up that sin?
Should there ever be a time when
as a church we're asking, well, why do
you want to talk about that sin?
If sin is sin and we know that sin only
gets worse and worse as time goes on,
how can we say that some sins are
getting better? Racism
that doesn't exist anymore. It's not
such a big deal anymore.
This sermon isn't about that. I I just
thought I'd put that in there just so
that people don't go back and say he
preached a whole sermon. No.
But I I'm using that as an illustration
to help you to understand, beloved, that
there is no sin that Satan traffics in
that gets better over time. No, no, no,
no, no. That's that's that's Darwinism.
That's evolution teaching.
The Bible tells us that things will get
worse as time goes on and that sin will
grow. The hearts of men will wax colder
as time goes on.
So now now we're in a place where we're
denying certain sins exist. Come on,
man. Why are you talking about that sin?
Like like literally Satan's getting
cover. We're co people are literally
covering for Satan.
Oh yeah, don't talk about that. Let's
leave that one alone. but talk about all
these other ones.
And so, beloved, what I'm trying to tell
you is that when you drop when your one
of the signs that you've been raptured
is when you drop when your garments are
found,
when you start calling good, evil, and
evil good.
Some people get raptured
in philosophies that are totally
anti-Bible. Hey, the Bible doesn't
condemn uh uh uh you know, alternative
lifestyles, so it's all right. You know,
you're making stuff up. The Bible
doesn't talk about about uh uh you know,
uh the gay lifestyle. No, no, no, no,
no. You're just making stuff up. And
some people get caught up in that way,
and others get caught up in the other
way. And beloved, I'm using those two
just as an example. Once once
philosophies of the world, whether
appearing to be righteous or openly
against the Bible, once you are caught
up, raptured,
the garments are always found.
You'll always see the garments found
because now you begin to call good evil
and evil good. But I want you to note
this in Matthew 22:8. There's a parable
Jesus gives for how he finds someone who
has entered in without the garments. It
says this. Then when he said, then he
saveth he to his servants, the wedding
is ready, but they were forbidden were
not worthy. Go ye therefore into the
highways and as many as you shall find
bid to the marriage. So those servants
sent went out to the highways and
gathered together all of them, as many
as they found, both bad and good, and
the wedding was furnished with guests.
And when the king came in to see the
guests, he saw there a man which had not
on a wedding garment.
And he saith unto him, "Friend, how
camest thou in hither not having a
wedding garment?" And he was speechless.
And you know the rest of the story. He's
cast out. Now, I need you to understand
something.
This man
that is found in the parable,
listen to me, y'all. The man
was not disinterested in heavenly
things.
How do we know that? Because he's at the
wedding.
He's there. If he wasn't interested, he
wouldn't be there. He wants to get in.
He believes that he belongs there.
But what he doesn't understand
it is that he's there without
his garments.
Why? He got caught up in something.
He got caught up in something that he
evidently thought was righteous.
Something that he evidently thought
would would get him into heaven. this is
the way
I'm good. As long as I have these check
marks, I'm good to go. I got a place in
the kingdom of heaven. Not realizing
that he had been caught up in a false
rapture.
And so, I want you to understand this,
beloved, that this ultimate catching up
is leading somewhere.
There's going to be, rather, I should
say there's going to be an ultimate
rapture, an ultimate catching up, and
the whole world is going to be raptured.
Y'all put a eight in the chat if you
understood what I just said. The whole
world is going to be raptured. The whole
world
is going to be caught up.
Revelation 13:13. Notice, notice it with
me on the screen. And he doeth great
wonders. He doeth great wonders, so that
he maketh fire come down from the from
heaven on earth in the sight of men, and
deceiveth them that dwell on the earth
by the means of those miracles which he
had power to do in the sight of the
beast, saying that they should make an
image to the beast, which had the wound
by the sword, and did live. In other
words, beloved,
this final rapture,
this final false rapture, this final
catching up,
the whole world's going to be caught up
in a delusion, in a lie.
It's going to be emotionally
gratifying. It's going to be emotionally
moving. And all those who have allowed
themselves to be moved
by emotion,
even while claiming to stand on the word
of God, but are moved on emotion,
caught up in things and movements and
trends and philosophies that cannot be
sustained by the word of God.
All of these many raptures that have
been happening are only preparing people
for the ultimate rapture that happens at
the end of time. Both outside the church
and inside the church.
Ephesians 4. Ephesians 4. Note what the
text says with me. Ephesians chapter 4
verse 13. till we all come into the
unity of the faith and of the knowledge
of the Son of God, unto a perfect man,
unto the measure of the stature and
fullness of Christ, that we henceforth
be no more children, tossed to and fro,
and carried about.
Carried about.
Caught up.
Caught up. Carried about. Caught up.
carried about by every wind of doctrine,
by the slight of men, and the cunning
craftiness whereby they lie in weight to
deceive.
Do you see?
Do you see what the enemy is doing here?
He's trying to get a whole bunch of
God's people caught up, tossed to and
fro.
tossed to and fro by conspiracies here
and conspiracies there and the
government this and this this and that
that and all and and and and this is
what's really happening and we got to do
this and we got to move with these
people. We got to connect with these
people because
all in the name of Jesus.
I want you to watch remember again.
Remember again in in 1 Thessalonians
chapter 4, for the Lord himself shall
descend from heaven with a shout. The
dead in Christ shall rise. Then we which
are alive and remain shall be caught up.
I want you to look at these two
definitions in Ephesians 4:4.
In Ephesians chapter 4:4, uh the word is
peripheral, carried about. In
Thessalonians, the word is caught up
harposal.
Listen,
one
is a counterfeit movement. The other is
a final rescue.
There are many people being
peripheral,
carried about,
falsely caught up,
blown about
by the winds of doctrine, by the winds
of earthly philosophies, by the winds of
false Christian movements
claiming political authority,
caught up because, oh, we've got to be
on that side. They're the right side.
And and and in being caught up and
beginning to mimic
the very talking points,
the very defenses
of these movements that have already
been caught up by error.
Beloved, whether you're in the church or
out the church, how do you avoid false
raptures? How do you avoid getting
caught up?
It's simple.
By being grounded.
Can I say it again? By being grounded.
Listen. Listen. Psalm 16:8. I have set
the Lord always before me. Because he is
at my right hand. I shall not be moved.
I shall not be moved.
You understand?
When when we are grounded in the word of
God, it doesn't matter how juicy the
conspiracy looks. It doesn't matter how
how how convincing uh the movement is.
It doesn't matter. And you know, I'm not
moving.
I see the word and I hear what you're
saying, but I'm not moving. I'm not
getting Come on, everybody. Put it in
the Put it in the chat for me, please.
I'm not getting two words. I'm not
getting
caught
up.
Sometimes I feel like half of our church
has disappeared,
caught up, raptured.
Wait a minute. What?
Where are they? They're gone.
Where's Where's brother so and so?
Where's sister so and so? caught up
bodily still present
but reason-wise
spiritual senses
raptured.
Raptured I want you to note with me
Ephesians chapter 3:1 17. The Bible says
that Christ may dwell in your hearts by
faith that ye being rooted and grounded
in love. Watch that y'all. Do you see
that? If you are not grounded in love,
you will be caught up.
We're to be grounded in the truth. We're
to be grounded in love. Law and mercy. H
justice and mercy. If we're not grounded
in love, that we may be able to
comprehend with all saints what is the
breadth and length and depth and height
and to know the love of Christ which
passes knowledge that you might be
filled with all the fullness of God.
Listen yet, listen. Listen.
If you're filled with the fullness of
God, there's no way that the devil can
lift you up.
There is no way that the devil will
Look, if I if I invited you to the gym,
I'm just going to use the ladies. Okay,
ladies, if I invited you to the gym, no.
Okay,
so sometimes
I I will tell you I was in the gym a a
few weeks ago and so I do situps, right?
And I use um I use a 100 pound dumbbell
to do my sit-ups. So I started off like
less I don't know like 30 pounds or
whatever and I do sit-ups to failure.
Now I grab a So I want you to imagine a
100 pound dumbbell and I I lift the
dumbbell. Actually this one was 120
pounds. So let me correct that. 120
pounds. I lifted this gigantic dumbbell
and I'm walking with it over to where
I'm going to do my sit-ups. I I you know
drop the weight. I sit down and now I'm
like I got to pick this thing up. So
there was this lady trainer who was
training someone and I kind of was like,
you know, I was like, she passed by and
I was like, uh, excuse me. She was like,
yeah. I was like, could you pick that up
and hand it to me? And she was like a
really light like, you know, light lady.
She wasn't heavy. And I was like, I'm
just playing. I'm just playing. And she
was like, no, no, no. I got you. And I
was like, no, you don't got me. I'm just
She's like, no, no, no. I got you. and
she picked the [snorts] 120 pound weight
up. She was like, I'm a trainer. She
picked it up and handed it to me. And I
was just like, I I repent and I
apologize. And she started laughing.
The devil is strong,
don't get me wrong,
but if you are filled with the fullness
of God, there's no way the devil can
lift you and get you caught up in
anything. Put a one in the chat if you
understand what I'm saying. When you are
filled with the with God, the infilling
of the Holy Spirit, the devil will not
be able to lift you off the ground.
He will not be able to get you caught
up. And the reason so many of us are so
easily caught up
is because we don't have the weight of
the spirit in us.
We may talk a good talk.
We may we may believe all the right
things doctrinally.
But there is something in us that leads
us to be easily blown with the winds of
conspiracy, with the winds of suspicion,
with the winds
of whatever feels good
to the carnal heart in the name of
Jesus.
Let me tell you, beloved, why it's so
important that we be weighed down with
the spirit of God before this final
false rapture happens. And I'll show
you. Let's go to Daniel 11:40. Because
the Bible speaks of a time that a power
will come, and we're not going to get
into who that power is right now, but
the Bible says at the time of the end,
the king of the south shall push at him,
and the king of the north shall come
against him like a whirlwind. Now, just
pause right there.
I I'm just going to build on this
specific part of this verse. Okay?
Whoever this power is that is coming
like a whirlwind is for the purpose of
catching people up. That's what a
whirlwind does. A whirlwind lifts you
off of the ground.
A whirlwind gets you caught up
in something.
And if these little whirlwinds and these
little mini raptures are getting us
caught up now into movements and into
and into politics
so that we think we're calling evil good
and good evil or we we think we're
calling good good and evil evil, but
we're actually calling evil good and
good evil. If these small
raptures are getting us caught up,
what's going to happen when this
whirlwind hits?
I'm going to skip a slide. I just want
to go to this quote. A storm is coming,
relentless in its fury. Are we prepared
to meet it? That is from a book called
Testimonies Volume 8. And it's a
spiritual appeal.
A storm is coming, relentless in its
fury. Are we prepared to meet it?
Will you get caught up in the storm or
will you be grounded in the storm? In
Revelation 12:15, we see how the devil
operates. The Bible tells us in
Revelation 12:15, "The serpent cast out
of his mouth water as a flood after
after the woman that he might cause her
to be," Put it in the chat, everybody
carried carried away of the flood.
The devil is trying to get you caught
up, carried away.
There are millions of people that are
being carried away by the false doctrine
of the rapture right now. Yes, they are
caught up in a false teaching. And the
next time this comes around, no, the
rapture is going to happen on December
15th of 2026. They will be right there
to be caught up again, only to be let
down time after time after time after
time. And if they would only say, you
know what, enough of the emotional
stuff. Let me actually go to the Bible
and see what the Bible says. I don't
want to be caught up in error anymore.
If they would just go to the Bible,
>> they would no longer be caught up. If
they would just be say, "Lord, help me
be grounded in love, love for my
neighbor and love for you," they would
no longer be caught up. But it's when
you don't have real love for your
neighbor, that you easily get caught up
in political movements, in religious
movements that say, "Ah,
whatever, the neighbor is the enemy."
And the moment you view the neighbor as
the enemy, you have been carried away by
from God.
The moment you view the neighbor as the
enemy,
I don't care if you view the neighbor as
the enemy in the name of Jesus. The
moment you view the neighbor as the
enemy,
you have been caught up.
Jesus prayed for his enemies. Jesus
said, "Forgive them for they know not
what they do." Jesus died for his
enemies.
I'm going to go to Matthew chapter 7.
Matthew 7 24. Matthew 7:24. This will be
our closing verse, guys. Matthew 7,
beginning with verse 24. Jesus said
this, "Therefore, whosoever he hearth
these sayings of mine and doeth them, I
will liken him unto a man which built
his house upon a rock."
And the rain descended,
and the floods came, and the winds blew
everybody.
The winds blew and beat upon that house,
and it fell not, for it was founded upon
a rock. And everyone that hearth these
sayings of mine, and doeth them not,
shall be likened unto a foolish man,
which built his house on the sand. And
the rain descended, and the floods came,
and the winds blew, and beat upon that
house, and it fell, and great was the
fall of it.
Great was the fall of it.
Beloved, this message
you suspected it was about the rapture
and
it it was about the rapture,
but it was about a whole lot more than
just
a false doctrine.
The underlying problem
of people getting caught up in the false
doctrine of the rapture
is trusting
in rapturous feeling rather than the
word of God.
Trusting in emotion and popularity and
trends.
Well, most people believe this, so I'm
going to believe it, too. rather than
believing in the word of God. And
sometimes as those who know better, we
we we think of ourselves as inoculated
from such deceptions.
All the while, people in the church are
disappearing,
friendships being broken,
just people disappearing. Where's the
guy I used to know?
Where's the girl I used to know?
Where's the friend I used to have?
Where have they gone?
Raptured.
Yes.
People in the church are disappearing.
Disappearing by a secret rapture.
Disappearing.
getting caught up in things that
that are not found in the Bible.
And so when I said earlier that the
rapture is happening right now and will
continue to happen and will culminate in
a great event at the end of time. I hope
you now understand
what I mean.
And beloved, we need to pray.
We need to pray that we not be raptured.
We need to pray
that we not be raptured in a false
rapture. We need to pray that those who
have been raptured will come back to the
word of God.
And we need to pray that those who are
being raptured by false doctrines
will have their eyes open
by returning to the word of God.
Because right now, right now, the world,
the Christian world
is getting caught up in something that
is very, very dangerous.
particularly here in America.
And many people
have been raptured,
raptured,
caught up
in this very dangerous thing that is
happening here in America.
And so
our prayer is three-fold. Lord,
I pray for the people that are being
caught up in false doctrine. Lord, I
pray for myself that I will not be
caught up in false raptures. And Lord, I
pray for the people,
my brothers and sisters
who have disappeared,
raptured,
caught up.
Bring them back
to be grounded in your word.
So you know which appeal belongs to you.
I'm going to ask you to put that one in
the chat.
put that one in the chat. And if there
is someone watching who has not who has
said, you know, I've been struggling
with either coming back to the Lord,
you may have been you may be raptured
right now and you're saying, whoa, how
did I get here and you're saying, "Lord,
I need to come back. I need to get back
down to the ground. I need to get
grounded again. I I went down this
rabbit hole and that rabbit hole and
that rabbit hole and now I don't even
know where in the rabbit hole I am. I've
been raptured. I've disappeared. Lord,
bring me back to a solid foundation of
your word.
This appeal is for you.
I if
you have been say you have said in your
in your in your heart, you know what,
I've yet to fully give my life to Christ
and I'm seeing things happening around
me now that I always thought that I'll
never see those things, but I'm seeing
these things now. Lord, it's time for me
to come. It's time for me to make that
decision. It's time for me to come back
into the fold because you left it
because you were unhappy about this or
that. It's time. I pray make that
decision now.
If you're home and you need to stand to
your feet, you could put a one in the
chat or a two in the chat or say that
here I am, Lord. Put your put your
response in the chat. If you're home and
you need to stand up, I invite you to
stand to your feet. If that's what you
need to do to reaffirm your to affirm
your commitment whether it's giving your
life your life to Christ for the first
time or coming back to the truth or or
coming out get leave asking the Lord to
deliver you from the thing you've been
raptured up in
stand if you need to stand do what you
need to do but respond beloved respond
to the appeal
respond to the appeal
I don't have any music here, but if you
need music in the background, play it in
your head. Do what you need to do.
But please stand, y'all.
We are running out of time. No man knows
the day or the hour, but I tell you, we
are running out of time.
I'm not saying this as an alarmist. I'm
not saying this as one who is always
like look you know this is right around
the corner. No but I'm telling you the
things that we are seeing unfold
in our country today
are things that many of us never thought
we would see in this country in our
lifetime.
And people
are literally being raptured before our
eyes.
Please y'all
stand
and having done all to stand,
stand on the word of God and stand in
love.
Heavenly Father,
we thank you for speaking.
We thank you Lord for revealing to us
the false raptures that are happening
all around us
now. Please Lord, we pray
for every decision that has been made.
Those who have who are saying, "Lord,
bring me down from where I've been
raptured. Bring me back. Plant me firmly
on the word of God."
For those who are seeing these things
happen in our nation and are realizing
that the things that have always that we
have prophesied for years
are now coming to pass and they're ready
to come back to the full. Lord, please
bring them back. Please
settle them in the truth.
And for those who have yet to give their
lives to Christ, Lord, I pray settle
them in the truth as well. Lord, I pray
for all who are getting caught up in
false doctrines that are not found in
the Bible, that they will no longer be
raptured away by false teachers and
false teachings.
Lead them to the word of God, to an
indepth study, that they may no longer
be caught up in error.
And Lord, finally,
I pray
Lord that we will be grounded in the
truth and that the spirit of Christ will
be so heavy in us that the devil will
not be able to catch us up. Thank you,
Lord. Thank you for hearing and for
answering our prayer because we ask it
in the precious and holy name of Jesus.
Amen. And amen.
We're going to going to go ahead and put
that last slide on the screen for those
of you who uh would like to get um
either the slides or connected with our
Bible worker for for uh Bible study. If
you're interested in baptism or you just
want to connect with Living Man online
or you have prayer requests, there it
is. All the information is right there.
We typically have an afterglow where we
get together and discuss um the contents
of the message, but we're not going to
be doing that today. Um we will uh pick
it up again next week. And again, guys,
may God bless you. May God uh uh keep
you grounded and rooted in his word.
Amen. And amen. And amen.